<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[White Peak Software Blog]]></title>
  <link href="http://blog.whitepeaksoftware.com/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://blog.whitepeaksoftware.com/"/>
  <updated>2013-11-27T07:45:49-05:00</updated>
  <id>http://blog.whitepeaksoftware.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Kirby Turner]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <rights>Copyright (c) 2003-2013 White Peak Software Inc</rights>
  
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Woohoo! White Peak Software is 10 Years Old]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.whitepeaksoftware.com/2013/11/27/woohoo-white-peak-software-is-10-years-old/"/>
    <published>2013-11-27T00:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2013-11-27T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.whitepeaksoftware.com/2013/11/27/woohoo-white-peak-software-is-10-years-old</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>On November 23 White Peak Software celebrated 10 years of being in business. This is a huge milestone for me as there have been times, even recently, when I’ve thought about quitting. But despite the rough patches, I can’t image being happier working elsewhere.</p>

<p>The idea to start White Peak Software came during my honeymoon 10 years ago. My lovely bride and I were at a swim-up bar in Hawaii having a couple of drinks while watching the Yankees play in the 2003 World Series. Out of the blue I said to her, “I think I’m going to start my own company when we return to New York.” She thought the idea was great. She knew I was unhappy with my current employer, and she felt I would be much happier working for myself. Little did she know what she was agreeing to. Obviously she was still high from the buzz of getting married.</p>

<p>I started the process of incorporating the moment we returned from our honeymoon, and on November 23, 2003, White Peak Software was born. The problem was, I didn’t know what I wanted to do with White Peak. The company was born out of frustration more than anything else. I had a good paying, six-figure job, a nice two-bedroom West Village apartment, and no debt. Life was good, but I had become very bitter towards the company I was working for. I knew I needed a change and starting my own company seemed like the right thing to do at the time.</p>

<h2 id='my_first_client'>My First Client</h2>

<p>Within a couple of weeks of White Peak’s official start I had my first part-time consulting gig. I wasn’t sure what I wanted to do with my company, so I took advantage of the fact that I had been a consultant for most of my career. This was how I was able to land the contract gig so quickly. However as quickly as I got the contract, I quickly realized the client wasn’t the ideal client for me so I fire them.</p>

<p>Firing my first client wasn’t a big deal at the time because I was still employed full time with my previous employer. I hadn’t quit my full-time job because I was in the middle of a project. I didn’t want to abandon the project, so I agreed I would stay on until the end of the project. Given the experience with my first White Peak Software client and the fact that I still had my full-time job elsewhere, I decided to put White Peak on hold until I could work on it full time.</p>

<p>I used this “on-hold” time to get affairs in order for White Peak. I worked on building the company website, I setup a corporate bank account, hired an accountant, bought computer equipment, read many books on building a company, and did other tasks so that when the time came White Peak would be ready for me to start full-time.</p>

<h2 id='fulltime_finally'>Full-time Finally</h2>

<p>My first day as a full-time employee at White Peak Software came on Monday, August 2, 2004. I remember the day like it was yesterday. I was sitting in my “office,” which was actually our spare bedroom overlooking Christopher Street in the West Village. I thought to myself, “Now what?” I sat in my office all day just starring at a blank screen on my computer. Occasionally I would spin my chair towards the window to watch the many people walking up and down Christopher Street.</p>

<p>This went on for a few days. I was, for the first time ever, working for myself full time, but I had no clue what I should be doing. I knew I needed to make money, after all we were living in Manhattan where the rent ain’t cheap, but I didn’t know what I should do to make money. I couldn’t use my contacts from my previous employer due to legal agreements, so I sent out emails to my professional contacts made while living in St. Louis a few years earlier. Those contacts were more than 5 years old, and a lot had changed in those 5 years. Still, I was hopeful I would land something. Unfortunately it didn’t happen.</p>

<p>I went 3 months without any income, and I blew through all of our savings during that time, most of which was my wife’s money. It was probably around this time when she first started worrying about what she had agreed to and helped encourage a year earlier at that swim-up bar in Hawaii.</p>

<h2 id='a_turning_point'>A Turning Point</h2>

<p>Things did start turning around during the second 3 months. I signed up on websites like guru.com to find freelance projects. I didn’t land anything big, but I had a little cash rolling in. My big break came 7 or 8 months after I started working full-time. A friend of my wife’s family owned a web design studio and they needed a contract programmer to do some ASP.NET work. I jumped on the opportunity, and I was finally feeling busy. In fact, it was around this time that more work started coming in, even from my old St. Louis contacts. A year after going full-time I had more work than I could handle.</p>

<p>I had so much work coming in that I started hiring freelancers to help out. Unfortunately this didn’t free up as much of my time as I had hoped. I was becoming a manager, and that wasn’t something I wanted to do. One of the things that excited me about having my own company was being a code monkey. Past employers wanted me to move up the corporate ladder, managing and leading others instead of coding. It was because of my coding skills and ability to deliver quality software that my past bosses thought I should play a bigger role. But they were clueless about the fact that what I love most is slinging code.</p>

<p>I hired freelancers to handle the growing demand for project work, but I found myself doing exactly what past bosses were doing with me. I was moving myself into a higher role, managing other developers and doing business development work to land new business deals. This wasn’t what I wanted to do with my company, but at the same time I didn’t know exactly what I wanted to do. All I knew was I needed to make money if I was going to continue being self-employed.</p>

<h2 id='in_need_of_therapy'>In Need of Therapy</h2>

<p>It was around this time that I hired a good friend of mine, Brian Harp. I hired Brian to be my small business coach, and each week for three months we met and talked about what I needed to do with my business. It was like going to therapy sessions but for my business. In the end, Brian helped me realize that what I needed to do was turn White Peak Software into a product company. It would be a small company, a company of one, focused on making and selling software products. Back then (and still today), those in the Microsoft world called this type of company a Micro-ISV, but I preferred the Mac community term of indie developer.</p>

<p>The term “indie developer” resonated with me. It conjured up thoughts of indie musicians, artists, and movie directors, people who are independent, people who pursue a love, a passion instead of focusing on making tons of money. Even to this day, I would rather do what I love than have infinite amounts of cash. Sure, having tons of cash makes it easier to do what you love, and most people think they have to pursue and acquire that large amount of cash before doing what they love. But I believe differently and I follow a different path. I&#8217;d rather do what I love today and be broke than to do what I hate just to make money so that hopefully, some day in the future, I might be able to do what I love.</p>

<p>My sessions with Brian made it clear to me what I wanted out of White Peak Software. I want to do what I love, which is to write code and build software that I care about. Also I want to make enough money to pay the bills by selling my own software. So in the summer of 2005 I released my first software product, SMTP Diagnostics.</p>

<h2 id='my_first_product'>My First Product</h2>

<p>SMTP Diagnostics was a tool I had written for myself to test email connections between web services and mail hosts. I found that often times while working in the corporate world, the web server didn’t have access to mail server, and yet, the web applications I worked on needed to send emails. And often times the IT infrastructure guy responsible for configuring the server, firewall, and so on would forget about email. So I wrote this little tool to test the connectivity between the web and mail servers. I would then report my findings back to the Mr. IT Infrastructure Guy proving the two servers were not in communicating with each other.</p>

<p>I enhanced and polished SMTP Diagnostics, then I released it into the wild. I didn’t really expect a lot of people to buy it. Instead I used the app as an opportunity to learn what is needed to sell software online. I learned how to implement trial periods, licensing keys, hosting an online shopping cart, payment processing, and most importantly handling customer support. To my surprise people did buy SMTP Diagnostics though not a lot. Still I deemed the app a success because I learned what I needed to take on a bigger product.</p>

<h2 id='my_second_product'>My Second Product</h2>

<p>With my first product out the door and people buying it, it was time to start work on my second app. At the same time contract work and the cash that comes with it distracted me. It would be almost two years later before I shipped my second product.</p>

<p>Killink CSV Editor was released in March 2007. My dev friends made fun of me, and still do, for releasing a CSV editor. We dev types think of CSV as being an out of date file format. JSON and XML are where it’s at. But the truth is, many large corporations including banks, hospitals, and online marketing companies use CSV files every day, and the people who deal with CSV files need a better way to edit their files. Killink CSV Editor was a great success, and it has been White Peak Software’s flag ship product since 2007.</p>

<h2 id='returning_to_fulltime_consulting'>Returning to Full-time Consulting</h2>

<p>With the excitement of Killink CSV Editor I decided to make a key decision about the future of White Peak Software. I told myself that if I hit a certain financial goal by the end of June 2007, I will stop providing consulting services for the rest of the year with the goal of focusing on improving Killink CSV Editor and starting work on my third product. If I missed my financial goal, then my plan would be to provide consulting services full time for 6 months to raise cash. This cash would allow me to focus on product development throughout 2008 without needing to do any consulting.</p>

<p>Unfortunately I missed my financial goal by a couple of thousands of dollars. Because I missed my financial goal I accepted a full-time consulting gig that would have me splitting my time between New York City and Bermuda. Not a bad gig, and it paid well.</p>

<h2 id='big_life_change'>Big Life Change</h2>

<p>A week after accepting the gig I found out my wife was pregnant. Within a couple of months the nesting feelings started to take effect on my wife and me. Long story short, I ended the gig early and instead of using the cash to invest in my business we bought a house in Salem, Massachusetts.</p>

<p>To this day, I have mixed emotions about buying the house. We bought it in December 2007 just as the market was crashing. It was not a good time to buy, but at the same time, I felt it might be the last time an indie developer could get a <a href='http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/No_doc_loan'>“no-doc” loan</a>. By the way, the name no-doc isn’t a fitting name because I had to provide hundreds of pages of documentation including statements from my accountant explaining my income, where the money for the down payment was coming from, and how we would be able to make monthly payments. Needless to say, it was a very stressful time.</p>

<p>By December 2007 I owned a house, had zero cash because we spent it all as the down payment on the house, and I had left a great consulting gig. Oh, and we had a baby coming. On top of this I took 6 weeks off from work to get the house ready for us to move into.</p>

<p>We finally moved into our house at the end of January 2008, and with the kid due in 2 months I decided to avoid any long term client projects. Because of the extended time off, I let the pipeline of work dry up. Between leaving the gig early and focusing all my time and energy on preparing the house, I put myself into a situation where I had no potential client work and the only income I was earning was from my software product. It would seem I was living the dream, but unfortunately my two apps were not making enough money for us to live on.</p>

<h2 id='the_first_iphone_sdk_beta'>The First iPhone SDK Beta</h2>

<p>It was around this time, March 2008 to be exact, that I learned about the iPhone SDK beta. I had made the move to the Mac in 2007, and I was planning to release a Mac version of my CSV editor. A neighbor of mine was a Apple fanboy who was super excited about the potential opportunity with the App Store. I wasn’t doing any client work at the time, and my son Rowan had just been born. I thought it was the perfect time to partner with my neighbor and get an app into the App Store just in time for the store’s launch.</p>

<p>After a couple of months it was clear to me the partnership wasn’t working out. My neighbor wasn’t doing anything to help build our app. I was doing all the work while he day dreamed about us making tons of money. I decided it was time to step away from our project, but there wasn’t enough time remaining for me to create my own app before launch day of the App Store, so I returned to consulting.</p>

<p>In August 2008, I won an iPod touch as a door prize for the second ever <a href='http://buildguild.org'>Build Guild</a>. Up until this time I didn’t own an iPhone or an iPod touch. I relied on the iPhone Simulator and my neighbor’s iPhone for testing. But ending our partnership meant I had no test device. I felt winning the prize was a sign that I needed to revisit the iPhone SDK, and in October 2008 I released my first iPhone app, Labor Mate.</p>

<h2 id='my_third_product'>My Third Product</h2>

<p>Labor Mate is a contraction timer for pregnant women. The first version, which was never submitted to Apple, took me a weekend to write. That was enough time to realize I needed to make the app real. Plus, the app was the perfect small app for me to work on since the whole experience with having a kid was still fresh in my mind.</p>

<p>The goals for Labor Mate were similar to SMTP Diagnostics, to learn the ins and outs of the App Store. I didn’t expect it to sell. But to my surprise, people did buy it. In fact, this 99 cent app started making more money per month than the CSV editor. Ah, the good ole days of the App Store…</p>

<h2 id='starting_over'>Starting Over</h2>

<p>It was around this time I decided I needed to refocus on my goal of turning White Peak Software into a product company. I set a company goal of releasing a new product each year. My thinking was to offer 5 to 7 apps total with hopes of having at least 4 of them bring in between $700 to $1500 per month in net revenue. This would put me well beyond the financial goal I set back in 2007, and once I met that goal I could stop consulting. However, I had a problem. I still didn’t feel comfortable with Cocoa, Objective-C, and the iPhone SDK. And without the necessary knowledge, I knew it would take me a lot of time to write those additional apps.</p>

<p>I decided what I needed was to work with Objective-C full time, and given that I worked for myself I knew I could make that call. At this time I had a good set of repeat clients for consulting gigs. Sure, there were times I would let the pipeline dry up, but I could get it flowing again in a short amount of time thanks to these repeat clients. The consulting work I did centered around web development with .NET, and writing C# code wasn’t helping me advance my Objective-C and Cocoa knowledge. So in January 2009 I “fired” all clients so I could focus on Mac and iPhone development full time.</p>

<p>I didn’t exactly fire them, but I told all my clients that I would be transitioning from web development to mobile development targeting the iPhone. If they had a need for a mobile (or Mac) app, then I was their guy. But if they did not have a need, then I would help them find a replacement. Unfortunately none of my clients were interested in mobile development at that time. (Side note, that has since changed and I have built iOS apps for some of them in recent years.)</p>

<p>In many ways, my decision to focus on mobile development meant I was starting over with my company. My goal was to write and sell my own apps, but I also had to pay the bills. We owned a house and had a kid. I couldn’t just live on pennies eating nothing more than ramen noodles every day. So I used my consulting skills and started looking for work as an iPhone developer.</p>

<h2 id='game_changer'>Game Changer</h2>

<p>Similar to when I started working for White Peak Software full time in August 2004, I went nearly 6 months before I started making money as an app developer. The game changer for me was <a href='http://www.360idev.com'>360|idev</a>. The people I met and the connections I made at my first 360, as well as at other 360|idev conferences, made it possible for me to make a living as an app developer.</p>

<p>By 2010 I had released a number of apps into the App Store. Granted these apps were for clients, but still, I was writing apps and loving it. I was also getting more involved in the Mac and iOS developer communities. I not only attended more conferences, such as <a href='http://nsconference.com'>NSConference</a> and <a href='https://developer.apple.com/wwdc/'>WWDC</a>, I started speaking at conferences. I also got involved with the local <a href='http://www.cocoaheadsboston.org'>Boston CocoaHeads</a>, and eventually I started my own monthly gathering of Mac and iOS developers in Salem called <a href='http://www.nshappyhour.org'>NSHappyHour</a>. My career was booming, so much so that I was approached to write a book for Addison Wesley on <a href='http://www.learningipadprogramming.com'>learning iPad programming</a>. I also released White Peak Software’s third app, Hey Peanut, which was a photo app for toddlers (and a total flop).</p>

<h2 id='the_book_oh_the_book'>The Book, Oh The Book</h2>

<p>The original hope for the book was to have it completed in 6 months. I viewed it as another product, and I felt it fit into my goal of having 5 to 7 products. Friends and family, including my wife, suggested I not pursue the book idea. But writing a tech book was a goal of mine, it had been for years. Even back in 2005 I had typed up an outline for a programming how-to book, but I never got around to submitting the proposal to publishers. Here was an opportunity for me to write a book, and the publisher had approached me. I saw this as a once in a life time opportunity with a well respected publisher. How could I say no?</p>

<p>I was thrilled about writing the book, but it turned out I had no clue what I was doing. I knew how to write software and more specifically I knew the iOS SDK — by this time Apple renamed iPhone SDK to iOS SDK — inside and out, but I didn’t know a damn thing about writing a book. I got a couple of chapters out quickly then I hit a block. I’ll save the details of my writing experience for another time, but suffice to say, I didn’t finish the book in 6 months. Instead it took me 18 months.</p>

<p>Riding the buzz of finishing the book, I agreed to do a video training session based on the book, which was released a few months after the book. Woohoo! Another product in my mind. I then started thinking about the second edition of the book. In all, I devoted two and half years to <a href='http://www.learningipadprogramming.com'>Learning iPad Programming</a>.</p>

<p>The time spent on the book wasn’t a full-time gig. There were small periods of time when I did consulting work to help pay the bills, and I had a couple of really good years selling my software products. While it seemed like I was living the dream, I made one critical mistake. I was ignoring White Peak Software.</p>

<p>In December 2012, I finished the manuscript for the second edition of the book. It was finally time to return my focus on White Peak Software. And so here we are, the year 2013.</p>

<h2 id='start_overagain'>Start Over…Again</h2>

<p>2013 has been a rough year, and I’m paying the price for ignoring White Peak Software while working on the both editions of the book. App sells are way down, and even the second edition of the book isn’t selling well. I’ve had some success this year with client work, but over all this year hasn’t gone as planned. Not only that, I’ve lost the momentum, and product revenue, that grew each year up through 2011.</p>

<p>I decided 2013 would be a reboot year for White Peak Software. It’s my third time starting over. I retired two apps at the first of the year. This action might seem sad, but it wasn’t. In fact it felt good to say bye to those apps, and it lifted a mental burden from my shoulders. Also this summer I started work on a new app, but I realized it will take me a lot of time to finish the app given its size.</p>

<p>Deciding I needed a quick win and a motivational boost, I wrote and released <a href='http://www.whitepeaksoftware.com/big-screen'>Big Screen</a> a couple of weeks ago. I don’t know if Big Screen will be a hit or a dud, but it doesn’t matter. My goal with this app was to get me back into the “ship it” mindset and to remind me how great it feels to create and release my own app. Just the simple act of shipping Big Screen had already made it a success for me.</p>

<p>So that’s the 10 year history of White Peak Software. Things haven’t gone quite as planned, and there are times when I thought of calling it quits. But looking back I see I’m happier than ever working for White Peak Software. It’s been an amazing 10 years, and I’m looking forward to another 10 years.</p>

<h2 id='lessons_learned'>Lessons Learned</h2>

<p>Before I go, I would like to share a few key things I have learned over the last 10 years in hopes that it will help others succeed at being an independent software developer.</p>

<ol>
<li>
<p>Don’t give up. There are going to be some hard times, and giving up will seem like the easy way out. Giving up is easy to do and very tempting, but as Kevin Hoctor recently said on <a href='https://alpha.app.net/kevinhoctor/post/15283389'>ADN</a>, “The only true failure is giving up.”</p>
</li>

<li>
<p>Learn from your mistakes. You’re going to make mistakes, and you’re going to have setbacks. But without them you will never learn. You learned to walk by first falling, and you’ll learn to succeed by making mistakes and having setbacks.</p>
</li>

<li>
<p>Seek feedback, advice, and opinions from others, but make your own decisions. I have found seeking the advice from other indie developers, business owners, and entrepreneurs helps me see all points of view. But at the end of the day, it’s up to me to make the decisions. If I always listened to and followed the advice from others, then I would have never created apps like Killink CSV Editor and Labor Mate. Listen to what others have to say, but make the decisions you feel are right for you.</p>
</li>

<li>
<p>Take chances. My second passion in life is snowboarding. One of the things I’ve learned from snowboarding is to push myself beyond my comfort zone. If I never pushed myself, I would never have discovered the joys of snowboarding. Likewise, if I didn’t take chances, if I didn’t push myself beyond my comfort zone, I would not be sitting here writing about the 10th anniversary of White Peak Software.</p>

<p>You never know if your app will be a hit or not. This is also true for your business or whatever else it is you want to pursue. You just don’t know what will work and what will fail. But I can guarantee you instant failure if you never take a chance and try. You’ll never know if you can write a hit app if you never take the chance to write the app. You’ll never know if you can survive as an indie developer or business owner, if you never take the chance to work for yourself. Take chances and push yourself beyond your comfort zone. The worse can happen is you fail, but that’s a good thing because we learn from our failures. Taking chances and pushing yourself out of your comfort zone will make you that much better in whatever you pursue.</p>
</li>

<li>
<p>Define what success means to you, and don’t be swayed by others telling you their definition of success. Success means different things to different people, and one person’s definition of success might not align with your definition. For some, success means making a ton of money. For others, it is spending quality time with family. What does success mean to you?</p>
</li>
</ol>

<p>You may have picked up on the fact that I define what success means for each of my apps and the definition isn’t necessarily the same for each app. Success doesn’t have to mean millions of downloads or thousands of dollars earned. Success can be based on what you learned, experience or how the experience motivates you to do more.</p>

<p>My definition for success with White Peak Software is to live the life I want here and now, today, and not wait for some future time after I have, quote un-quote, retired. Sure, I’m not where I thought I would be with White Peak Software after 10 years and we’re definitely not living on Easy Street with regard to our finances, but the last 10 years have still been successful. This year, for example, is the year my family and I moved to a ski town, which has been a goal of ours for years. The likelihood of this happening would have been much less if I hadn’t taken the chance of starting White Peak Software 10 years ago.</p>

<p>White Peak Software has been successful in helping me reach my goals in life, and it will continue to help me reach new goals…hopefully for at least another 10 years if not longer.</p>

<p>Happy anniversary, White Peak Software.</p>]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[ANN: Big Screen Out in the Wild Early]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.whitepeaksoftware.com/2013/11/17/big-screen-out-in-the-wild-early/"/>
    <published>2013-11-17T00:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2013-11-17T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.whitepeaksoftware.com/2013/11/17/big-screen-out-in-the-wild-early</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Last night I made a <a href='https://twitter.com/kirbyt/status/401882700048781312'>teaser tweet</a> about <a href='http://www.whitepeaksoftware.com/big-screen'>Big Screen</a> being approved by Apple. The idea was to pique interest in the app I plan to release in a few weeks. But silly me, I forgot to set the available date to a date in the future, and soon after my tweet people were downloading Big Screen. As my friend <a href='http://www.goldenhillsoftware.com'>John Brayton</a> said, I need to “think of it as extending a beta to anyone on the app store.” So with that, I’m happy to announce Big Screen is now available to everyone.</p>

<p>Big Screen is a new app for iOS that displays the camera’s video stream to any AirPlay receiver (i.e., AppleTV). What makes Big Screen different from using, say the built-in Camera app, is that Big Screen does not display any application chrome on the AirPlay receiver. This makes Big Screen ideal for presentations, conferences, and other types of gatherings where large TV monitors are used to show what’s happening on stage to the folks sitting in the back of the room.</p>

<p>There are other uses for Big Screen as well. My son, and other kids, have been using it to play a version of hide and seek. And kids in general seem to enjoy seeing themselves on TV and are finding ways to have fun with Big Screen that I never thought of. I should also mention that while Big Screen is free, I do have plans to hopefully make a few bucks off the app. The next update will include ads (that are displays on the device, not on the AirPlay receiver) and an In-App Purchase option to remove the ads from the app.</p>

<p>So go grab a copy of <a href='http://www.whitepeaksoftware.com/main/store/buy/big-screen'>Big Screen</a>, and let me know what you think.</p>]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[ANN: Learning iPad Programming, 2nd Edition, is on Sale Now]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.whitepeaksoftware.com/2013/05/28/learning-ipad-programming-on-sale-now/"/>
    <published>2013-05-28T00:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2013-05-28T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.whitepeaksoftware.com/2013/05/28/learning-ipad-programming-on-sale-now</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I&#8217;m happy to announce the second edition of <a href='http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/0321885716/ref=as_li_ss_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;camp=1789&amp;creative=390957&amp;creativeASIN=0321885716&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;tag=whitepeaksoft-20'>Learning iPad Programming</a> is now available at your favorite book store.</p>]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[ANN: Product Retirements]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.whitepeaksoftware.com/2013/01/02/ann-product-retirement/"/>
    <published>2013-01-02T00:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2013-01-02T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.whitepeaksoftware.com/2013/01/02/ann-product-retirement</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>It&#8217;s a brand new year, and as the saying goes, out with the old and in with the new.</p>

<p>I mentioned in my <a href='/2012/12/29/year-in-review/'>2012 Year in Review</a> post that I&#8217;m re-focusing my intention on White Peak Software this year. In some was this re-focus is like a re-boot for WPS. This means exciting new things for the company going forward, but it also means it&#8217;s time to good bye a couple of products.</p>

<p>The first product retiring is SMTP Diagnostics. SMTP Diagnostics was White Peak Software&#8217;s very first product. I honestly did not know if the app would sell or not, nor did I care. I released it because, at the time, it was an app I needed and used regularly. The release of SMTP Diagnostics also gave me the opportunity to learn how to sell software online. Without SMTP Diagnostics, I would not have been as prepared for the other White Peak Software apps.</p>

<p>The second product retiring today is Hey Peanut. Hey Peanut was written for my son Rowan, who was only one and a half at the time. I had high hopes for Hey Peanut. My son loved the app, and I thought other kids would enjoy it as well. I invested time and money into the app, but unfortunately I missed the mark with it. All is not lost though. I learned a lot from the mistakes I made with Hey Peanut that will help me going forward.</p>

<p>It saddens me to see these two apps removed from the White Peak Software home page. Both are very special to me in their own ways. But it is a new year, so out with the old and in with the new.</p>]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[ANN: Office is Open]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.whitepeaksoftware.com/2012/09/10/office-is-open/"/>
    <published>2012-09-10T00:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2012-09-10T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.whitepeaksoftware.com/2012/09/10/office-is-open</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The White Peak Software office is once again open. It&#8217;s back to business as usual.</p>]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[ANN: Office Closed August 22 Through End of September]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.whitepeaksoftware.com/2012/08/20/office-closed/"/>
    <published>2012-08-20T00:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2012-08-20T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.whitepeaksoftware.com/2012/08/20/office-closed</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The White Peak Software office will be closed from Wednesday, August 22, through the end of September.</p>

<p>I am leaving for a month long backpacking trip starting on August 22, and I plan to return by the end of September. Unfortunately I will not have Internet access during this trip, which is why the office will be closed. I apologize in advance for any inconvenience this might cause.</p>

<p>All support emails will be answered in the order they are received once I return.</p>

<p>If you have lost your license information and need it re-sent, click <a href='http://www.whitepeaksoftware.com/support/licenselookup'>here</a> and provide the email address used when the order was placed. Your license information will be retrieved and sent to you via email.</p>

<p>An update to this blog will be posted as soon as the White Peak Software office returned to normal operations.</p>]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Wanted: Beta Testers for Killink CSV Editor]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.whitepeaksoftware.com/2011/06/28/wanted-beta-testers-for-killink-csv-editor/"/>
    <published>2011-06-28T00:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2011-06-28T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.whitepeaksoftware.com/2011/06/28/wanted-beta-testers-for-killink-csv-editor</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I posted a new beta for Killink CSV Editor v2 today. The big feature added to version 2 is Unicode support. This means Killink CSV Editor can now read and write not only ASCII files but UTF-8 and UTF-16 files.</p>

<p>If you&#8217;re a Killink CSV Editor user and you want to live life on the edge, please <a href='http://cdn.whitepeaksoftware.com/downloads/setup-killinkcsv-250.exe'>download beta 2</a>, give it a test drive, and send email to <em>support at white peak software dot com</em> if you encounter any issues. Note this build of Killink CSV Editor installs, by default, in a separate directory allowing both Version 1.14 and Version 2.0 to co-exists on the same computer.</p>]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[ANN: Hey Peanut 1.3 is in the App Store]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.whitepeaksoftware.com/2010/08/26/ann-hey-peanut-1-3-is-in-the-app-store/"/>
    <published>2010-08-26T00:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2010-08-26T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.whitepeaksoftware.com/2010/08/26/ann-hey-peanut-1-3-is-in-the-app-store</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Hey Peanut 1.3 is now available in the App Store. The 1.3 update to Hey Peanut includes a new safari theme and all new animal sound effects.</p>

<p>What is Hey Peanut? Hey Peanut is a photo app for toddlers available on iPhone and iPad. Parents add pictures to Hey Peanut and optionally record a message on each picture. Then your 1 to 3 year old can flip through the pictures, touching each one to hear the recorded message. Hey Peanut also includes colorful themes with fun sound effects to entertain your child.</p>

<p>Keep an eye on the <a href='http://twitter.com/heypeanutapp'>@HeyPeanutApp</a> and <a href='http://twitter.com/whitepeak'>@WhitePeak</a> Twitter feeds for free promo codes.</p>

<p><img alt='HeyPeanut-1.3-preview2.png' src='/images/blog/2010-08-26-HeyPeanut-1.3-preview2.png' /></p>]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[ANN: Hey Peanut 1.2 is in the App Store]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.whitepeaksoftware.com/2010/07/07/ann-hey-peanut-1-2-is-in-the-app-store/"/>
    <published>2010-07-07T00:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2010-07-07T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.whitepeaksoftware.com/2010/07/07/ann-hey-peanut-1-2-is-in-the-app-store</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I&#8217;m happy to announce version 1.2 of Hey Peanut, the photo app for toddlers available on the iPhone and iPad, is now available in the App Store. This update fixes bugs reported on iOS4 and adds new HD artwork for iPhone 4.</p>]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[ANN: Labor Mate 1.7 is in the App Store]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.whitepeaksoftware.com/2010/07/02/ann-labor-mate-1-7-is-in-the-app-store/"/>
    <published>2010-07-02T00:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2010-07-02T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.whitepeaksoftware.com/2010/07/02/ann-labor-mate-1-7-is-in-the-app-store</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The latest version of Labor Mate, the best dang labor contraction timer for the iPhone and iPod touch, is now available in the App Store. This update is FREE to existing user. The update includes a much improved UI, compatibility with iOS4 and multitasking, and support for the new retina display on iPhone 4.</p>]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Hey Peanut - iPad App for Toddlers]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.whitepeaksoftware.com/2010/04/02/hey-peanut-ipad-app-for-toddlers/"/>
    <published>2010-04-02T00:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2010-04-02T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.whitepeaksoftware.com/2010/04/02/hey-peanut-ipad-app-for-toddlers</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Hey Peanut version 1.1 has just been released and is available in the App Store. I&#8217;m very excited about this update because it adds support for the new iPad, which will be available for purchase tomorrow. Best of all the update is free to existing users, so if you already bought Hey Peanut and you are getting an iPad then you will get the iPad version of Hey Peanut for free as well.</p>

<p>Haven&#8217;t bought Hey Peanut for your toddler? No worries. The price will remain $1.99 and will include both the iPhone and iPad versions. It&#8217;s like getting 2 apps for the price of 1.</p>

<p><img alt='HeyPeanut-iPad-Sample.png' src='/images/blog/2010-04-02-HeyPeanut-iPad-Sample.png' /></p>]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Hey Peanut for the iPhone is in the App Store]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.whitepeaksoftware.com/2010/03/17/hey-peanut-for-the-iphone-is-in-the-app-store/"/>
    <published>2010-03-17T00:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2010-03-17T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.whitepeaksoftware.com/2010/03/17/hey-peanut-for-the-iphone-is-in-the-app-store</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I&#8217;m very excited to announce the immediate availability of Hey Peanut in the App Store. Hey Peanut is a new type of photo browser on the iPhone and iPod touch designed specifically for your toddler, ages 1 to 3 years old. Hey Peanut is kid tested and parent approve. It includes fun farm animals and sound effects to entertain your little one, but the best feature is the built-in voice recorder.</p>

<p>Add photos of family and friends then have them record a voice message for your child. When you child touches the photo the voice recording will play. This is a great way for your child to see and hear love ones who might live or be out of town.</p>

<p>My son Rowan, at the age of 20 months, helped me design Hey Peanut. He played with Hey Peanut at every stage. He hated it in the beginning, always saying &#8220;No, no!&#8221; But once all the pieces were in place, the music, farm scenes, and sound effects, he loved it. He now plays with Hey Peanut often and especially enjoys seeing and hearing his mom when she is out of town working.</p>

<p>If you have love ones who live out of town, or a parent that travels often, then you toddler is going to love Hey Peanut.</p>]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Labor Mate 1.6 is Now Available]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.whitepeaksoftware.com/2010/02/05/labor-mate-1-6-is-now-available/"/>
    <published>2010-02-05T00:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2010-02-05T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.whitepeaksoftware.com/2010/02/05/labor-mate-1-6-is-now-available</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Labor Mate 1.6 has been approved by Apple and is now available in the App Store. This version fixes the problem with the No button displayed after touching the Reset button.</p>]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Donating $150 to Haiti as Part of Indie+Relief]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.whitepeaksoftware.com/2010/01/21/donating-150-to-haiti-as-part-of-indierelief/"/>
    <published>2010-01-21T00:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2010-01-21T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.whitepeaksoftware.com/2010/01/21/donating-150-to-haiti-as-part-of-indierelief</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The final sales numbers are in for White Peak Software. $150 was raised by our customers as part of <a href='http://www.indierelief.com/'>Indie+Relief</a>. A big THANKS to all who participated.</p>

<p>Because it is such a good cause I decided to do something a little different. The original plan was to donate all proceeds from the sales on January 20. However, additional processing fees are taken out of each transaction - 30% to Apple and 15% to eSellerate. I decided I will donate the cost of the transaction fees myself.</p>

<p>Here is a breakdown of sales for the donation:</p>

<p>ProductUnits SoldUnit CostTotal</p>

<p>Labor Mate 42 $0.99 $41.58</p>

<p>Killink CSV Editor 3 $27.00 $81.00</p>

<p>SMTP Diagnostics 2 $11.95 $23.90</p>

<p><strong>Grand Total</strong></p>

<p><strong>$146.48</strong></p>

<p>I rounded the grand total up to <strong>$150</strong>. The money has been donated to <a href='http://www.doctorswithoutborders.org/'>Doctors Without Borders</a> as part of the emergency relief for Haiti.</p>

<p>Finally, I want to send a big THANKS for <a href='http://twitter.com/justin'>Justin Williams</a> of <a href='http://www.secondgearsoftware.com/'>Second Gear Software</a> for coming up with the idea and <a href='http://twitter.com/garrettmurray'>Garrett Murray</a> who built the Indie+Relief web site. Both individuals put a great deal of time and effort to make this event happen in just a matter of days.</p>]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Donate to Haiti Relief Efforts and Get Great Software]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.whitepeaksoftware.com/2010/01/14/donate-to-haiti-relief-efforts-and-get-great-software/"/>
    <published>2010-01-14T00:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2010-01-14T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.whitepeaksoftware.com/2010/01/14/donate-to-haiti-relief-efforts-and-get-great-software</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I will be donating all proceeds from White Peak Software product sales on Wednesday, January 20, 2010, as part of the <a href='http://www.indierelief.com/'>Indie+Relief</a> program. The proceeds will be donated to <a href='http://doctorswithoutborders.org/'>Doctors Without Borders</a> to assist with their efforts in Haiti.</p>

<h2 id='how_can_you_help'>How can you help?</h2>

<p>You can help by purchasing one of our products: Labor Mate, Killink CSV Editor, or SMTP Diagnostics. Don&#8217;t have a need for one of our products? Then visit the <a href='http://www.indierelief.com/'>Indie+Relief</a> website for a list of other independent software companies participating in this Haiti relief program.</p>

<p><a href='http://www.indierelief.com/'>Get great software and help with efforts in Haiti at the same time.</a></p>]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Coming Soon: NSiPhoneDevs]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.whitepeaksoftware.com/2010/01/08/coming-soon-nsiphonedevs/"/>
    <published>2010-01-08T00:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2010-01-08T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.whitepeaksoftware.com/2010/01/08/coming-soon-nsiphonedevs</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Over the last few months I have been inspired by different iPhone developer community events including <a href='http://www.360idev.com/'>360iDev</a> and <a href='http://drinksontap.org/'>DrinksOnTap</a>. So much so I have decided to start my own monthly <a href='http://nsiphonedevs.org'>event for Boston area iPhone developers</a>.</p>

<p>The opportunity to meet fellow iPhone developers and form new friendships is very exciting to me and it motivates me to do more with White Peak Software. Working from home is a wonderful perk of being an indie developer but it can be lonely at times. Meetup events, conferences, and so on are great ways for me to feel connected. And it gives my wife a needed break from my geek talk, which she doesn&#8217;t always understand but always happily smiles and acts like she is interested.</p>

<p>The Boston area has a number of meetup events but it is not always possible for me to get into Boston. And let&#8217;s face it. <a href='http://mbta.com/'>MBTA</a> ain&#8217;t the <a href='http://mta.info/'>MTA</a>. I missed the 10:40 pm train to Salem at the last event I attended in Cambridge. This meant waiting until the 12:10 am train. I finally got home at 1 am.</p>

<p>So what&#8217;s a North Shore iPhone developer who can&#8217;t always make it into Boston to do? Start a monthly gathering in the North Shore of course.</p>

<p>Over the New Year&#8217;s weekend I <a href='http://twitter.com/kirbyt/status/7305792560'>tweeted</a> about a new group I&#8217;m creating called <a href='http://nsiphonedevs.org/'>NSiPhoneDevs</a>. The NS prefix is a fun play on the prefix for many of the foundation classes from Apple, but the NS prefix also stands for &#8220;North Shore&#8221;. The North Shore iPhone Developers or NSiPhoneDevs for short.</p>

<p>I&#8217;m still working out the details including the exact location. What I do know is the events will be held in downtown Salem, the events will be monthly, and the first event will be this spring. Stay tune for more NSiPhoneDevs news from the official website (<a href='http://nsiphonedevs.org/'>http://nsiphonedevs.org/</a>) or follow <a href='http://twitter.com/nsiphonedevs'>@NSiPhoneDevs</a> on Twitter.</p>]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Selected as a 360iDev San Jose Speaker]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.whitepeaksoftware.com/2010/01/07/selected-as-a-360idev-san-jose-speaker/"/>
    <published>2010-01-07T00:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2010-01-07T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.whitepeaksoftware.com/2010/01/07/selected-as-a-360idev-san-jose-speaker</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Yesterday I was having a very good day but around 5:45 pm my day got even better. I received an email from the fine folks at 360iDev that my topic &#8220;Building Web Service Powered iPhone Apps&#8221; has been selected. Yep, that&#8217;s right folks. I will be speaking at the upcoming <a href='http://www.360idev.com/'>360iDev San Jose</a> (April 11-14).</p>

<p>I&#8217;m very excited about this opportunity for a number of reasons. First and foremost, speaking at the conference gives me a chance to share what I have learned over the recents months about leveraging web services within iPhone applications. I have worked with web services in some form for over a decade now so it&#8217;s only natural that I would gravitate towards using them in iPhone applications. I also plan to blog more on the topic as I prepare my materials for the conference.</p>

<p>Another reason I&#8217;m excited about speaking at 360iDev this spring is I get to attend the conference. I was on the fence about going. I&#8217;m already registered for <a href='http://nsconference.com/'>NSConference 2010 USA</a> and I plan to attend this year&#8217;s WWDC. I actually was planning to email John at 360iDev to ask if there are plans for another event later in the year. 360iDev Denver was such an incredible experience I knew I didn&#8217;t want to go the entire year without attending at least one event. But before I got the chance to ask about another event this year I received the email accepting me as a speaker. This of course made my decision easy. Heck yeah I&#8217;m going in April!</p>

<p>And the final reason I&#8217;m excited about this opportunity, 360iDev events are the best. Granted I have attended only 1 and that was last fall, but it was by far the best developer conference I have attended in recent years. And definitely one of the top conferences I have ever attended. I posted <a href='http://blog.whitepeaksoftware.com/2009/10/13/360idev-denver-a-personal-review/'>my comments about 360iDev Denver</a> back in October so I will not repeat myself here. What I will say, though, is if you are an iPhone developer then you should attend 360iDev San Jose. I guarantee you will pick up a trick or two or twelve and best of all you will get to meet other awesome iPhone developers.</p>]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Suport Forums to Move to Google Groups]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.whitepeaksoftware.com/2009/12/31/suport-forums-to-move-to-google-groups/"/>
    <published>2009-12-31T00:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2009-12-31T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.whitepeaksoftware.com/2009/12/31/suport-forums-to-move-to-google-groups</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>On January 1, 2010, the official support groups for all White Peak Software products will moving to Google Groups. The new URLs are below:</p>

<p>Labor Mate</p>

<p><a href='http://groups.google.com/group/whitepeaksoftware-labormate'>http://groups.google.com/group/whitepeaksoftware-labormate</a></p>

<p>Killink CSV Editor</p>

<p><a href='http://groups.google.com/group/whitepeaksoftware-killinkcsveditor'>http://groups.google.com/group/whitepeaksoftware-killinkcsveditor</a></p>

<p>Why the move? The old forum software I used was becoming a pain to host and keep running. Also, almost all support questions and bug reports I receive come via email and not via the support forum. In other words, the this support forum was rarely used. And frankly I do not like web forums. I prefer email.</p>

<p>Google Groups offers the best of both, web forums for those who prefer it and email for those who rather interact with a community via email. I know the move will be a pain for the select few who use this forum especially if don&#8217;t already have a Google Account. But the small pain outweighs the benefits of the move.</p>

<p>Also, I hope this move will help the online community to grow. Time will tell if that happens or not.</p>

<p>No support group URL for SMTP Diagnostics? Support for SMTP Diagnostics will be email only going forward. Use the <a href='http://whitepeaksoftware.com/main/default/contact'>contact us</a> page to send your questions and bug reports.</p>]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[ANN: Labor Mate 1.5 in App Store]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.whitepeaksoftware.com/2009/11/18/ann-labor-mate-1-5-in-app-store/"/>
    <published>2009-11-18T00:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2009-11-18T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.whitepeaksoftware.com/2009/11/18/ann-labor-mate-1-5-in-app-store</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I&#8217;m pleased to announce the release of Labor Mate version 1.5, which is now available in the App Store. This release fixes a few bugs but more importantly it adds support for 8 new languages. Labor Mate now supports the following languages:</p>

<ul>
<li>Dutch</li>

<li>French</li>

<li>German</li>

<li>Italian</li>

<li>Japanese</li>

<li>Spanish</li>

<li>Swedish</li>

<li>Russian</li>
</ul>

<p>Labor Mate is available for only $0.99 in the <a href='http://whitepeaksoftware.com/main/store/buy/labor-mate'>iTunes App Store</a>.</p>]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Labor Mate v1.4 Available in the App Store]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.whitepeaksoftware.com/2009/10/25/labor-mate-v1-4-available-in-the-app-store/"/>
    <published>2009-10-25T00:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2009-10-25T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.whitepeaksoftware.com/2009/10/25/labor-mate-v1-4-available-in-the-app-store</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The newest version of Labor Mate, version 1.4, is now available in the App Store. This new release includes an improved user interface as well as some bug fixes.</p>]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>