<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[White Peak Software Blog]]></title>
  <link href="http://blog.whitepeaksoftware.com/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://blog.whitepeaksoftware.com/"/>
  <updated>2015-11-20T12:01:41-05:00</updated>
  <id>http://blog.whitepeaksoftware.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Kirby Turner]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <rights>Copyright (c) 2003-2015 White Peak Software Inc</rights>
  
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Special Offer For Killink CSV Editor Customers]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.whitepeaksoftware.com/2015/11/20/special-offer-for-killink-csv-editor-customers/"/>
    <published>2015-11-20T11:47:27-05:00</published>
    <updated>2015-11-20T11:47:27-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.whitepeaksoftware.com/2015/11/20/special-offer-for-killink-csv-editor-customers</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I recently made the tough decision to <a href="http://blog.whitepeaksoftware.com/2015/08/18/killinks-retirement/">retire</a> Killink CSV Editor. This retirement means new licenses for the CSV editor are no longer available for purchase.</p>

<h2 id="but-what-does-this-mean-for-existing-killink-csv-editor-customers">But what does this mean for existing Killink CSV Editor customers?</h2>

<p>Nothing changes. If you previously purchased a Killink CSV Editor license, then you can continue using the editor. And I’m available to answer any questions you might have about the editor.</p>

<p>I do understand some of you may prefer using a CSV editor that is gaining new features and improvements. That’s why I’m happy to share with you a nice offer from the makers of <a href="http://www.ronsplace.eu/Products/RonsEditor">Ron’s Editor</a>, another outstanding CSV editor for Windows.</p>

<h2 id="free-rons-editor-license">Free Ron’s Editor License</h2>

<p>Existing Killink CSV Editor customer are eligible to receive a FREE license to Ron’s Editor. Claiming the free license is easy as 1-2-3.</p>

<ol>
  <li>
    <p>Visit: <a href="https://www.ronsplace.eu/Products/RonsEditor/Partner/WhitePeak">https://www.ronsplace.eu/Products/RonsEditor/Partner/WhitePeak</a></p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Enter your Killink CSV Editor license key, then click Find.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Enter your name and email address, then click Send.</p>
  </li>
</ol>

<p>That’s it. You will receive an email containing your new license key for Ron’s Editor.</p>

<p>To learn more about Ron’s Editor, the Ultimate CSV Editor, visit their <a href="http://www.ronsplace.eu/Products/RonsEditor">website</a>. You can also download a trial version of the editor if you want to try it out before taking advantage of this offer.</p>

<p>To learn more about why I decided to retire Killink CSV Editor, read this <a href="http://blog.whitepeaksoftware.com/2015/08/18/killinks-retirement/">post</a>.</p>

<h2 id="thank-you">Thank You</h2>

<p>Finally, to Killink CSV Editor customers, thank you for your understanding with this tough decision. And thank you for your support of Killink CSV Editor over the years. It’s individuals like you that keep small businesses like mine running.</p>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[ANN: Killink's Retirement]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.whitepeaksoftware.com/2015/08/18/killinks-retirement/"/>
    <published>2015-08-18T11:03:48-04:00</published>
    <updated>2015-08-18T11:03:48-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.whitepeaksoftware.com/2015/08/18/killinks-retirement</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The time has come to retire Killink CVS Editor. This is not an easy decision for me to make. But with the recent release of Windows 10 and the lack of active development work going into Killink, I feel it is time.</p>

<p>A big part of me hates to see this product come to an end. It is a great app and many people rely on it daily. I tried multiple times over the years to find a new home for Killink, but I didn’t have any luck.</p>

<p>Sales of Killink have slowly dropped over the years as well, and rightfully so. I’ve not actively worked on the app in the while nor have I actively marketed the app.</p>

<p>The combination of falling sales, the lack of active development, the release of a new version of Windows and the unsuccessful attempts to find a new home for Killink CSV Editor have all led to my decision to retire it.</p>

<p><strong>What does this retirement mean for current users of Killink CSV Editor?</strong></p>

<p>For the loyal customers who bought a Killink CSV Editor license, nothing changes. You can continue using the app.(<sup id="fnref:1"><a href="#fn:1" class="footnote">1</a></sup>) This includes installing and using the app on new computers. And I will continue providing support for the app by answering your questions and helping you if you happen to encounter a problem using the app.</p>

<p>Nothing changes for the licensed user, but for those without a license, well, I’m sorry to say you can no longer purchase a license. As part of this retirement, new licenses are no longer available for purchase.</p>

<p>I know this decision to stop selling new licenses will disappoint some folks, and I full expect to receive some angry emails over the next few months. All I can say is I’m sorry.</p>

<p><strong>Why not make the app free?</strong></p>

<p>I thought about offering Killink as a free app, but I feel this would be a metaphoric slap in the face to those who paid for the software. Plus, I’m still providing support to those customers who already bought a license.</p>

<p>Making the app free to everyone would mean I have to also offer support to non-paying customers as there is no easy way for me to distinguish between those who paid and those who didn’t. Or the alternative would be ending support all together just so others can use the software for free, but that isn’t fair either to the folks who paid for the software. So Killink will not be re-released as a free app.</p>

<p>To those who have purchase Killink CSV Editor and continue to use it today, I thank you for your support over the years. And please know that even though new licenses can no longer be purchased, you can continue using your license and the software for as long as you like.(<sup id="fnref:1:1"><a href="#fn:1" class="footnote">1</a></sup>)</p>

<hr />

<div class="footnotes">
  <ol>
    <li id="fn:1">
      <p>If you have a paid license, you can continue using Killink CSV Editor well into the future as long as the version of Windows you are using supports running older software. Best efforts will be made to offer continuous support on newer versions of Windows, but there is no guarantee the software will run on future versions of Windows. <a href="#fnref:1" class="reversefootnote">&#8617;</a> <a href="#fnref:1:1" class="reversefootnote">&#8617;<sup>2</sup></a></p>
    </li>
  </ol>
</div>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[ANN: Peak App Care]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.whitepeaksoftware.com/2015/08/13/ann-peak-app-care/"/>
    <published>2015-08-13T09:35:25-04:00</published>
    <updated>2015-08-13T09:35:25-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.whitepeaksoftware.com/2015/08/13/ann-peak-app-care</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I’m excited to announce a new service from White Peak Software called <a href="https://www.peakappcare.com">Peak App Care</a>. Peak App Care is a monthly subscription service for maintaining your iOS apps. What do I mean by that? Simply put, we monitor your app for crashes and fix them as quickly as possible. Not only that, we perform small jobs such as bug fixes and enhancements to your app at your request, and we even manage the App Store for you, from updating screenshots to submitting new builds on your behalf.</p>

<p>To Learn more about this new service, visit the new <a href="https://www.peakappcare.com">Peak App Care website</a>.</p>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Quickly Post Photos To Facebook]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.whitepeaksoftware.com/2015/03/25/quickly-post-photos-to-facebook/"/>
    <published>2015-03-25T07:40:55-04:00</published>
    <updated>2015-03-25T07:40:55-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.whitepeaksoftware.com/2015/03/25/quickly-post-photos-to-facebook</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Last night a friend of mine was trying to post photos to Facebook. We were at <a href="http://www.stowecider.com">Stowe Cider</a> for their Cider House Rules event, which, by the way, was a lot of fun. Unfortunately for my friend the Facebook app was slow to load and it crashed a few times on her iPhone. The slow Internet connection was the likely cause of the problem, but even if the Internet connection had been better, my friend would still have to wait for the Facebook app to do its thing before she could post the photos. That’s when I showed her my app, <a href="http://www.whitepeaksoftware.com/cross-post">Cross Post</a>.</p>

<p>Cross Post sends your post to Facebook and Twitter. It doesn’t download your timeline or stream, so you don’t have to worry about the app taking a long time to load. But there is another feature of Cross Post that makes it even easier and faster to share photos: the share extension.</p>

<p>With the Cross Post share extension, you can access Cross Post from virtual any app on your iPhone and iPad. As an example I showed my friend how easy it is to share a new photo from the Camera app. I took a picture. I tapped the picture thumbnail in the lower left corner of the Camera app screen. I tapped the Share icon - that’s the one of a rectangle with an up arrow coming out of the top. I tapped the Cross Post icon, typed in a message, selected Facebook, and sent off the picture for my friends on Facebook to enjoy.</p>

<p>It sounds like a lot of steps when you write it out like that, but it really isn’t as you can see in this short <a href="https://vimeo.com/123186958">video</a>.</p>

<div class="vimeo-video"><figure><iframe src="//player.vimeo.com/video/123186958" width="500" height="281" frameborder="0" webkitallowfullscreen="" mozallowfullscreen="" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></figure></div>

<p>The share extension isn’t limited to sharing photos either. You can use it to share links and text from other apps as well.</p>

<p>Wanna try Cross Post for free? Just <a href="https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/cross-post/id872543786?mt=8&amp;uo=4&amp;at=11lcj9&amp;ct=blog">download it</a> from the App Store.</p>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[2014 Year In Review]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.whitepeaksoftware.com/2015/01/01/2014-year-in-review/"/>
    <published>2015-01-01T11:09:30-05:00</published>
    <updated>2015-01-01T11:09:30-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.whitepeaksoftware.com/2015/01/01/2014-year-in-review</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Here we are, January 1, 2015. I decided not to write a 2014 Year in Review post, but then this morning I read some <a href="http://www.startupclarity.com/blog/bootstrappers-2014-year-review">2014 year in reviews</a> from other bootstrappers, which in turned led to me re-read my own reviews from <a href="http://blog.whitepeaksoftware.com/2009/12/30/white-peak-software-year-in-review-2009/">2009</a>, <a href="http://blog.whitepeaksoftware.com/2012/12/29/year-in-review/">2012</a>, and <a href="http://blog.whitepeaksoftware.com/2013/11/27/woohoo-white-peak-software-is-10-years-old/">2013</a>. Actually the 2013 review is more of a <a href="http://blog.whitepeaksoftware.com/2013/11/27/woohoo-white-peak-software-is-10-years-old/">10 years in review</a>, but it still talks about what happened with White Peak Software in 2013. After reading these other posts, I changed my mind about writing a 2014 Year in Review post, so without further ado here is my 2014 Year in Review.</p>

<h2 id="a-quick-look-back">A Quick Look Back</h2>

<p>2014 didn’t go as planned. This is becoming a common theme with me. My long term goal is to turn White Peak Software into a product company, but I still struggle to make that happen. My biggest hurdle is life. My life responsibilities are much different today than they were when I first set out to build a product company many years ago. And the amount of debt I now have is much different as well.</p>

<p>There was a time when I had no real responsibilities…no significant other in my life, no kid, no house, no debt, no bills other than rent, utilities, and Internet access. I might be living the snowboard bum’s life now, but I also have real responsibilities too…a family to provide for, a mortgage to pay as well as rent (we still own our house in Salem and are currently renting here in Stowe), and debt. Lots of debt. And it is this debt that has the biggest impact on me and White Peak Software.</p>

<p>We (the personal “we”, not the company “we”) have tenants living in the house in Salem, which covers the mortgage for us. And we have reduced most of our expenses down to the bare necessities. But those two and half years focused on writing caused us to go deep into debt. And it is this debt that keeps distracting me from my ultimate goal of focusing my time on building and selling my own products.</p>

<p>Paying off the debt has become priority number one for me, and the fastest way for me to do this is to offer my skills to others as a consultant/contract programmer. And that’s pretty much what I did for most of 2014.</p>

<p>I started 2014, much like other years, with the hope of being more focused on product development, but an outstanding opportunity presented itself at the start of the year. It was a chance to work with a team, one I worked with years ago, to build a new e-Learning platform and application. I agreed to do the project, and I had a great time doing it. In the end we built an amazing solution for the end client. This project combined with a few smaller client projects got the cash flowing and the end results was the best revenue year ever for White Peak Software. Not only that I was able to reduce my personal debt by 25%.</p>

<p>The downside to all of this was I didn’t have as much time to focus on product development as I wanted, and I ended the year burnt out. In fact, I’ve been burnt out since November, which has caused its own set of problems. Still, I was able to find some time to write and release my latest app, <a href="http://www.whitepeaksoftware.com/cross-post">Cross Post</a>. So overall 2014 was a good year even if I ended the year burnt out and questioning White Peak Software’s future.</p>

<h2 id="accomplishments">Accomplishments</h2>

<p>I’m happy with my accomplishments for 2014 even though I didn’t stick with my original plans for the year. Those accomplishments include:</p>

<ul>
  <li>Completing four client projects, three of which are in the App Store today. The other was a proof of concept app for sports broadcast company.</li>
  <li>Releasing <a href="http://www.whitepeaksoftware.com/cross-post">Cross Post</a>, a new app for White Peak Software.</li>
  <li>Having revenue totals hit an all time high for the company.</li>
  <li>Paying off a quarter of my personal debt.</li>
  <li>Living a full year in a ski town as a snowboard bum.</li>
</ul>

<p>The last two accomplishments are not directly related to White Peak Software, but since White Peak is a solo operation those accomplishments are indirectly related to my company. And the last one is huge not just for me, but for my wife and son too.</p>

<h2 id="what-went-right">What Went Right</h2>

<p>So what went right for me in 2014? I earned a lot of cash, which is always a good thing, but I’m not sure I would say that qualifies as something that went right. Landing that big opportunity, now that’s something that went right. I should mention that the project was with a client that I used to work with years ago when I was a web developer. I’ve kept in touch with them over the years, which is why they thought of including me as part of the team. The lesson learned here is to always keep in touch with your favorite clients because you never know where it will lead down the road.</p>

<p>There are two other things that went right for me in 2014, 1) releasing <a href="http://www.whitepeaksoftware.com/cross-post">Cross Post</a> and 2) paying down debt.</p>

<p>Although most of my time in 2014 was devoted to client work, I did find time to work on and ship <a href="http://www.whitepeaksoftware.com/cross-post">Cross Post</a>. A key difference with this app versus every other piece of software I’ve ever written is that I use Cross Post daily. And that made all the difference in the world with me shipping the app. And I’m not done with it either. I have big plans for Cross Post for 2015.</p>

<p>And what more can I say about paying down debt? This is key in achieving my long term goals for White Peak Software. I hate that I let myself slide into debt after years of being debt free, but I’m happy to see the big drop in the amount owned. And I’m hoping to drop it down even more in 2015.</p>

<h2 id="what-didnt-go-so-well">What Didn’t Go So Well</h2>

<p>Look back there were two things that didn’t go well for me in 2014. And by “didn’t go well” I mean they really sucked big time. The first was a small client project I took on at the start of the year while waiting for the start of the big, awesome project. The small project called for about a week of my time. After six weeks long weeks and lots of stress I finally had to roll myself off the project. This is something uncharacteristic of me, but it was something that needed to be done. I feel bad about it, but I wasn’t the only one who left. A few other devs came and went during my short time on project.</p>

<p>The other thing that didn’t go well is I let myself get burnt out. I didn’t take breaks between projects. My plan was to take small breaks, but it didn’t happen and as a result I suffered from a major case of burn out in November that carried over into December. And I still haven’t fully recovered though my attitude and motivation has improved somewhat over the last couple of weeks.</p>

<h2 id="goals-for-2015">Goals for 2015</h2>

<p>And there you have it. My 2014 Year in Review. So what do I have planned for 2015? First and foremost is to focus more time on billable work. I know this is counter to my long term goals, but as I mentioned my number one priority right now is to pay off my outstanding debt. Admittedly I’m not bouncing off the wall with excitement at the idea of working full time on client projects, but I plan to approach it differently in 2015.</p>

<p>Unlike past years when I worked for different clients throughout the year, my plan for 2015 is to work with one primary client, or an anchor client as my accountant likes to call it. This means I will be less “indie” because I basically will be working for someone else, but it will save me tons of times by eliminating the need to do on-going business development work. Keeping the pipeline of opportunities open and flowing requires a great deal of time, so my plan for 2015 is to eliminate the business development work by working for the anchor client throughout the year. And I’ll replace the time usually spent on biz dev efforts with work on Cross Post and improving my other products.</p>

<p>So the tl;dr for my 2015 goals are:</p>

<ul>
  <li>Find a steady stream of revenue from an anchor client.</li>
  <li>Work on my products part-time.</li>
  <li>Pay down my personal debt.</li>
  <li>And get as much snowboarding and hiking in as possible.</li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[ANN: Cross Post v1.2 is in the App Store]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.whitepeaksoftware.com/2014/12/13/ann-cross-post-v1-2-is-in-the-app-store/"/>
    <published>2014-12-13T00:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2014-12-13T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.whitepeaksoftware.com/2014/12/13/ann-cross-post-v1-2-is-in-the-app-store</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The latest update to Cross Post has hit the App Store. This update fixes bugs and adds new features including:</p>

<ul>
  <li>A photo album picker.</li>
  <li>An option to attach the last photo taken.</li>
  <li>Smart quotes and punctuations.</li>
  <li><em>wpscrosspost</em> URL scheme for Launch Center Pro support</li>
</ul>

<p><a href="https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/cross-post/id872543786?mt=8&amp;uo=4&amp;at=11lcj9&amp;ct=blog">Download Cross Post</a> from the App Store now.</p>

<h2 id="smart-quotes">Smart Quotes</h2>

<p>To turn on smart quotes and punctuations, tap the post composer and select <strong>Use Smart Quotes</strong> in the edit menu. Select <strong>Use Dumb Quotes</strong> to turn it off.</p>

<p><img src="https://farm8.staticflickr.com/7524/15392871453_65c9d32fd2.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<h2 id="url-scheme">URL Scheme</h2>

<p><strong>wpscrosspost</strong> has been added as the custom URL scheme for Cross Post. You can use it to launch Cross Post from other apps. There is also a compose action that lets you set the post text and even attach the last photo.</p>

<p>To launch Cross Post, use the URL:</p>

<p><strong>wpscrosspost://</strong></p>

<p>To compose a new post, use:</p>

<p><strong>wpscrosspost://compose?text=[text]&amp;attachment=photo:last</strong></p>

<p>Both parameters are optional. The parameter <em>text</em> can be any text that you want to include in the post. The parameter <em>attachment</em> lets you attach a photo to the post. At the moment <strong>photo:last</strong> is the only supported value for <em>attachment</em> parameter.</p>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[ANN: Cross Post, Sharing Across Social Sites Made Simple]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.whitepeaksoftware.com/2014/11/20/ann-cross-post-sharing-across-social-sites-made-simple/"/>
    <published>2014-11-20T00:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2014-11-20T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.whitepeaksoftware.com/2014/11/20/ann-cross-post-sharing-across-social-sites-made-simple</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="http://257bf79813094f196f16-bc6ead213ec900841fcf0484ae93cd9e.r62.cf2.rackcdn.com/images/cross-post/crosspost-screenshot.png" alt="image" height="200px" style="float: left; margin: 0 1em 1em 0;" /> I am thrilled to announce the release of <a href="http://www.whitepeaksoftware.com/cross-post">Cross Post</a>, a new app for iPhone and iPad that makes it simple to share your post, photos, and links to Facebook, Twitter, and App.net. I talk in detail <a href="http://www.thecave.com/2014/09/14/cross-posting-to-app.net-facebook-and-twitter/">why I decided to write Cross Post</a> over on my personal blog site, but long story short, I wanted a better way to share my thoughts and photos across different social media sites. And <a href="http://www.whitepeaksoftware.com/cross-post">Cross Post</a> is that better way.</p>

<p>Cross Post is free to download and use, but it has limits. You can post to only one social media site at a time using the free version. This gives you a chance to try out Cross Post without spending a cent. If you decide Cross Post is right for you and you want to post to multiple social media sites at the same time, then unlock everything the app has to offer for just $2.99.</p>

<p>What are you waiting for? <a href="https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/cross-post/id872543786?mt=8&amp;uo=4&amp;at=11lcj9&amp;ct=blog">Download Cross Post</a> from the App Store now.</p>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[iOS Exclusive, Well, Not Really]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.whitepeaksoftware.com/2014/03/17/exclusive-ios-not-really/"/>
    <published>2014-03-17T00:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2014-03-17T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.whitepeaksoftware.com/2014/03/17/exclusive-ios-not-really</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Earlier today I was <a href="https://twitter.com/williamdnapier/status/445563171659849728">asked</a> if I’m exclusively iOS with regard to the work I do. My initial response was “yes”, but it occurred to me that I’m not exclusively an iOS developer. Sure, development work on iOS is my primary source of income, but I do work with other programming languages and platforms.</p>

<p>Prior to 2007, I’m focus was on Microsoft .NET using C#. I produced a number of B2B and back office solutions using ASP.NET with C#. I also did Windows desktop development using Delphi.</p>

<p>In 2007, I started experimenting with Xcode in hopes of porting <a href="http://www.whitepeaksoftware.com/killink-csv-editor">Killink CSV Editor</a> to the Mac. In the spring of 2008 I started playing with the first public beta release of the iPhone SDK. And by the fall of 2008 I released my first iPhone app.</p>

<p>It was clear to me at this time that I was hooked on Objective-C. I told my clients that I would be moving away from Microsoft technologies by the start of 2009 to focus on iPhone and Mac development. The transition was a tough one because at the time none of my clients were interested in mobile (though that has since changed and I’m now doing iOS work for some of those same clients). But thanks to the Cocoa developer community and events like <a href="http://www.360idev.com">360idev</a>, I weathered the worse of transition and I now focus my time on writing iOS and Mac apps. However, iOS and Mac apps are different today than they were back in 2008.</p>

<p>Most iOS and Mac apps today are connected apps, meaning they interact with a server. I haven’t written a single app in the last 2 years that didn’t have some sort of interaction with a server. And given my past experience with server work, I have made a point to keep up with what’s happening on the server side of things.</p>

<p>More recently I have been doing server work using Node.js primarily as a means to implement web services needed for the iOS and Mac apps that I work on. I also use python for a number of task, mainly for local scripts such as build scripts for my Xcode projects, but also I use python for the <a href="http://www.whitepeaksoftware.com">White Peak Software</a> company web site and for some Google App Engine work I’ve done as the backend for iOS apps.</p>

<p>So while it seems I’m exclusively an iOS developer, I’m not really. I build apps for iOS and Mac using Objective-C, and backend web services for those apps using python and Node.js. And I’m sure this too will change over time.</p>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Woohoo! White Peak Software is 10 Years Old]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.whitepeaksoftware.com/2013/11/27/woohoo-white-peak-software-is-10-years-old/"/>
    <published>2013-11-27T00:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2013-11-27T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.whitepeaksoftware.com/2013/11/27/woohoo-white-peak-software-is-10-years-old</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>On November 23 White Peak Software celebrated 10 years of being in business. This is a huge milestone for me as there have been times, even recently, when I’ve thought about quitting. But despite the rough patches, I can’t image being happier working elsewhere.</p>

<p>The idea to start White Peak Software came during my honeymoon 10 years ago. My lovely bride and I were at a swim-up bar in Hawaii having a couple of drinks while watching the Yankees play in the 2003 World Series. Out of the blue I said to her, “I think I’m going to start my own company when we return to New York.” She thought the idea was great. She knew I was unhappy with my current employer, and she felt I would be much happier working for myself. Little did she know what she was agreeing to. Obviously she was still high from the buzz of getting married.</p>

<p>I started the process of incorporating the moment we returned from our honeymoon, and on November 23, 2003, White Peak Software was born. The problem was, I didn’t know what I wanted to do with White Peak. The company was born out of frustration more than anything else. I had a good paying, six-figure job, a nice two-bedroom West Village apartment, and no debt. Life was good, but I had become very bitter towards the company I was working for. I knew I needed a change and starting my own company seemed like the right thing to do at the time.</p>

<h2 id="my-first-client">My First Client</h2>

<p>Within a couple of weeks of White Peak’s official start I had my first part-time consulting gig. I wasn’t sure what I wanted to do with my company, so I took advantage of the fact that I had been a consultant for most of my career. This was how I was able to land the contract gig so quickly. However as quickly as I got the contract, I quickly realized the client wasn’t the ideal client for me so I fire them.</p>

<p>Firing my first client wasn’t a big deal at the time because I was still employed full time with my previous employer. I hadn’t quit my full-time job because I was in the middle of a project. I didn’t want to abandon the project, so I agreed I would stay on until the end of the project. Given the experience with my first White Peak Software client and the fact that I still had my full-time job elsewhere, I decided to put White Peak on hold until I could work on it full time.</p>

<p>I used this “on-hold” time to get affairs in order for White Peak. I worked on building the company website, I setup a corporate bank account, hired an accountant, bought computer equipment, read many books on building a company, and did other tasks so that when the time came White Peak would be ready for me to start full-time.</p>

<h2 id="full-time-finally">Full-time Finally</h2>

<p>My first day as a full-time employee at White Peak Software came on Monday, August 2, 2004. I remember the day like it was yesterday. I was sitting in my “office,” which was actually our spare bedroom overlooking Christopher Street in the West Village. I thought to myself, “Now what?” I sat in my office all day just starring at a blank screen on my computer. Occasionally I would spin my chair towards the window to watch the many people walking up and down Christopher Street.</p>

<p>This went on for a few days. I was, for the first time ever, working for myself full time, but I had no clue what I should be doing. I knew I needed to make money, after all we were living in Manhattan where the rent ain’t cheap, but I didn’t know what I should do to make money. I couldn’t use my contacts from my previous employer due to legal agreements, so I sent out emails to my professional contacts made while living in St. Louis a few years earlier. Those contacts were more than 5 years old, and a lot had changed in those 5 years. Still, I was hopeful I would land something. Unfortunately it didn’t happen.</p>

<p>I went 3 months without any income, and I blew through all of our savings during that time, most of which was my wife’s money. It was probably around this time when she first started worrying about what she had agreed to and helped encourage a year earlier at that swim-up bar in Hawaii.</p>

<h2 id="a-turning-point">A Turning Point</h2>

<p>Things did start turning around during the second 3 months. I signed up on websites like guru.com to find freelance projects. I didn’t land anything big, but I had a little cash rolling in. My big break came 7 or 8 months after I started working full-time. A friend of my wife’s family owned a web design studio and they needed a contract programmer to do some ASP.NET work. I jumped on the opportunity, and I was finally feeling busy. In fact, it was around this time that more work started coming in, even from my old St. Louis contacts. A year after going full-time I had more work than I could handle.</p>

<p>I had so much work coming in that I started hiring freelancers to help out. Unfortunately this didn’t free up as much of my time as I had hoped. I was becoming a manager, and that wasn’t something I wanted to do. One of the things that excited me about having my own company was being a code monkey. Past employers wanted me to move up the corporate ladder, managing and leading others instead of coding. It was because of my coding skills and ability to deliver quality software that my past bosses thought I should play a bigger role. But they were clueless about the fact that what I love most is slinging code.</p>

<p>I hired freelancers to handle the growing demand for project work, but I found myself doing exactly what past bosses were doing with me. I was moving myself into a higher role, managing other developers and doing business development work to land new business deals. This wasn’t what I wanted to do with my company, but at the same time I didn’t know exactly what I wanted to do. All I knew was I needed to make money if I was going to continue being self-employed.</p>

<h2 id="in-need-of-therapy">In Need of Therapy</h2>

<p>It was around this time that I hired a good friend of mine, Brian Harp. I hired Brian to be my small business coach, and each week for three months we met and talked about what I needed to do with my business. It was like going to therapy sessions but for my business. In the end, Brian helped me realize that what I needed to do was turn White Peak Software into a product company. It would be a small company, a company of one, focused on making and selling software products. Back then (and still today), those in the Microsoft world called this type of company a Micro-ISV, but I preferred the Mac community term of indie developer.</p>

<p>The term “indie developer” resonated with me. It conjured up thoughts of indie musicians, artists, and movie directors, people who are independent, people who pursue a love, a passion instead of focusing on making tons of money. Even to this day, I would rather do what I love than have infinite amounts of cash. Sure, having tons of cash makes it easier to do what you love, and most people think they have to pursue and acquire that large amount of cash before doing what they love. But I believe differently and I follow a different path. I’d rather do what I love today and be broke than to do what I hate just to make money so that hopefully, some day in the future, I might be able to do what I love.</p>

<p>My sessions with Brian made it clear to me what I wanted out of White Peak Software. I want to do what I love, which is to write code and build software that I care about. Also I want to make enough money to pay the bills by selling my own software. So in the summer of 2005 I released my first software product, SMTP Diagnostics.</p>

<h2 id="my-first-product">My First Product</h2>

<p>SMTP Diagnostics was a tool I had written for myself to test email connections between web services and mail hosts. I found that often times while working in the corporate world, the web server didn’t have access to mail server, and yet, the web applications I worked on needed to send emails. And often times the IT infrastructure guy responsible for configuring the server, firewall, and so on would forget about email. So I wrote this little tool to test the connectivity between the web and mail servers. I would then report my findings back to the Mr. IT Infrastructure Guy proving the two servers were not in communicating with each other.</p>

<p>I enhanced and polished SMTP Diagnostics, then I released it into the wild. I didn’t really expect a lot of people to buy it. Instead I used the app as an opportunity to learn what is needed to sell software online. I learned how to implement trial periods, licensing keys, hosting an online shopping cart, payment processing, and most importantly handling customer support. To my surprise people did buy SMTP Diagnostics though not a lot. Still I deemed the app a success because I learned what I needed to take on a bigger product.</p>

<h2 id="my-second-product">My Second Product</h2>

<p>With my first product out the door and people buying it, it was time to start work on my second app. At the same time contract work and the cash that comes with it distracted me. It would be almost two years later before I shipped my second product.</p>

<p>Killink CSV Editor was released in March 2007. My dev friends made fun of me, and still do, for releasing a CSV editor. We dev types think of CSV as being an out of date file format. JSON and XML are where it’s at. But the truth is, many large corporations including banks, hospitals, and online marketing companies use CSV files every day, and the people who deal with CSV files need a better way to edit their files. Killink CSV Editor was a great success, and it has been White Peak Software’s flag ship product since 2007.</p>

<h2 id="returning-to-full-time-consulting">Returning to Full-time Consulting</h2>

<p>With the excitement of Killink CSV Editor I decided to make a key decision about the future of White Peak Software. I told myself that if I hit a certain financial goal by the end of June 2007, I will stop providing consulting services for the rest of the year with the goal of focusing on improving Killink CSV Editor and starting work on my third product. If I missed my financial goal, then my plan would be to provide consulting services full time for 6 months to raise cash. This cash would allow me to focus on product development throughout 2008 without needing to do any consulting.</p>

<p>Unfortunately I missed my financial goal by a couple of thousands of dollars. Because I missed my financial goal I accepted a full-time consulting gig that would have me splitting my time between New York City and Bermuda. Not a bad gig, and it paid well.</p>

<h2 id="big-life-change">Big Life Change</h2>

<p>A week after accepting the gig I found out my wife was pregnant. Within a couple of months the nesting feelings started to take effect on my wife and me. Long story short, I ended the gig early and instead of using the cash to invest in my business we bought a house in Salem, Massachusetts.</p>

<p>To this day, I have mixed emotions about buying the house. We bought it in December 2007 just as the market was crashing. It was not a good time to buy, but at the same time, I felt it might be the last time an indie developer could get a <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/No_doc_loan">“no-doc” loan</a>. By the way, the name no-doc isn’t a fitting name because I had to provide hundreds of pages of documentation including statements from my accountant explaining my income, where the money for the down payment was coming from, and how we would be able to make monthly payments. Needless to say, it was a very stressful time.</p>

<p>By  December 2007 I owned a house, had zero cash because we spent it all as the down payment on the house, and I had left a great consulting gig. Oh, and we had a baby coming. On top of this I took 6 weeks off from work to get the house ready for us to move into.</p>

<p>We finally moved into our house at the end of January 2008, and with the kid due in 2 months I decided to avoid any long term client projects. Because of the extended time off, I let the pipeline of work dry up. Between leaving the gig early and focusing all my time and energy on preparing the house, I put myself into a situation where I had no potential client work and the only income I was earning was from my software product. It would seem I was living the dream, but unfortunately my two apps were not making enough money for us to live on.</p>

<h2 id="the-first-iphone-sdk-beta">The First iPhone SDK Beta</h2>

<p>It was around this time, March 2008 to be exact, that I learned about the iPhone SDK beta. I had made the move to the Mac in 2007, and I was planning to release a Mac version of my CSV editor. A neighbor of mine was a Apple fanboy who was super excited about the potential opportunity with the App Store. I wasn’t doing any client work at the time, and my son Rowan had just been born. I thought it was the perfect time to partner with my neighbor and get an app into the App Store just in time for the store’s launch.</p>

<p>After a couple of months it was clear to me the partnership wasn’t working out. My neighbor wasn’t doing anything to help build our app. I was doing all the work while he day dreamed about us making tons of money. I decided it was time to step away from our project, but there wasn’t enough time remaining for me to create my own app before launch day of the App Store, so I returned to consulting.</p>

<p>In August 2008, I won an iPod touch as a door prize for the second ever <a href="http://buildguild.org">Build Guild</a>. Up until this time I didn’t own an iPhone or an iPod touch. I relied on the iPhone Simulator and my neighbor’s iPhone for testing. But ending our partnership meant I had no test device. I felt winning the prize was a sign that I needed to revisit the iPhone SDK, and in October 2008 I released my first iPhone app, Labor Mate.</p>

<h2 id="my-third-product">My Third Product</h2>

<p>Labor Mate is a contraction timer for pregnant women. The first version, which was never submitted to Apple, took me a weekend to write. That was enough time to realize I needed to make the app real. Plus, the app was the perfect small app for me to work on since the whole experience with having a kid was still fresh in my mind.</p>

<p>The goals for Labor Mate were similar to SMTP Diagnostics, to learn the ins and outs of the App Store. I didn’t expect it to sell. But to my surprise, people did buy it. In fact, this 99 cent app started making more money per month than the CSV editor. Ah, the good ole days of the App Store…</p>

<h2 id="starting-over">Starting Over</h2>

<p>It was around this time I decided I needed to refocus on my goal of turning White Peak Software into a product company. I set a company goal of releasing a new product each year. My thinking was to offer 5 to 7 apps total with hopes of having at least 4 of them bring in between $700 to $1500 per month in net revenue. This would put me well beyond the financial goal I set back in 2007, and once I met that goal I could stop consulting. However, I had a problem. I still didn’t feel comfortable with Cocoa, Objective-C, and the iPhone SDK. And without the necessary knowledge, I knew it would take me a lot of time to write those additional apps.</p>

<p>I decided what I needed was to work with Objective-C full time, and given that I worked for myself I knew I could make that call. At this time I had a good set of repeat clients for consulting gigs. Sure, there were times I would let the pipeline dry up, but I could get it flowing again in a short amount of time thanks to these repeat clients. The consulting work I did centered around web development with .NET, and writing C# code wasn’t helping me advance my Objective-C and Cocoa knowledge. So in January 2009 I “fired” all clients so I could focus on Mac and iPhone development full time.</p>

<p>I didn’t exactly fire them, but I told all my clients that I would be transitioning from web development to mobile development targeting the iPhone. If they had a need for a mobile (or Mac) app, then I was their guy. But if they did not have a need, then I would help them find a replacement. Unfortunately none of my clients were interested in mobile development at that time. (Side note, that has since changed and I have built iOS apps for some of them in recent years.)</p>

<p>In many ways, my decision to focus on mobile development meant I was starting over with my company. My goal was to write and sell my own apps, but I also had to pay the bills. We owned a house and had a kid. I couldn’t just live on pennies eating nothing more than ramen noodles every day. So I used my consulting skills and started looking for work as an iPhone developer.</p>

<h2 id="game-changer">Game Changer</h2>

<p>Similar to when I started working for White Peak Software full time in August 2004, I went nearly 6 months before I started making money as an app developer. The game changer for me was <a href="http://www.360idev.com">360idev</a>. The people I met and the connections I made at my first 360, as well as at other 360idev conferences, made it possible for me to make a living as an app developer.</p>

<p>By 2010 I had released a number of apps into the App Store. Granted these apps were for clients, but still, I was writing apps and loving it. I was also getting more involved in the Mac and iOS developer communities. I not only attended more conferences, such as <a href="http://nsconference.com">NSConference</a> and <a href="https://developer.apple.com/wwdc/">WWDC</a>, I started speaking at conferences. I also got involved with the local <a href="http://www.cocoaheadsboston.org">Boston CocoaHeads</a>, and eventually I started my own monthly gathering of Mac and iOS developers in Salem called <a href="http://www.nshappyhour.org">NSHappyHour</a>. My career was booming, so much so that I was approached to write a book for Addison Wesley on <a href="http://www.learningipadprogramming.com">learning iPad programming</a>. I also released White Peak Software’s third app, Hey Peanut, which was a photo app for toddlers (and a total flop).</p>

<h2 id="the-book-oh-the-book">The Book, Oh The Book</h2>

<p>The original hope for the book was to have it completed in 6 months. I viewed it as another product, and I felt it fit into my goal of having 5 to 7 products. Friends and family, including my wife, suggested I not pursue the book idea. But writing a tech book was a goal of mine, it had been for years. Even back in 2005 I had typed up an outline for a programming how-to book, but I never got around to submitting the proposal to publishers. Here was an opportunity for me to write a book, and the publisher had approached me. I saw this as a once in a life time opportunity with a well respected publisher. How could I say no?</p>

<p>I was thrilled about writing the book, but it turned out I had no clue what I was doing. I knew how to write software and more specifically I knew the iOS SDK — by this time Apple renamed iPhone SDK to iOS SDK — inside and out, but I didn’t know a damn thing about writing a book. I got a couple of chapters out quickly then I hit a block. I’ll save the details of my writing experience for another time, but suffice to say, I didn’t finish the book in 6 months. Instead it took me 18 months.</p>

<p>Riding the buzz of finishing the book, I agreed to do a video training session based on the book, which was released a few months after the book. Woohoo! Another product in my mind. I then started thinking about the second edition of the book. In all, I devoted two and half years to <a href="http://www.learningipadprogramming.com">Learning iPad Programming</a>.</p>

<p>The time spent on the book wasn’t a full-time gig. There were small periods of time when I did consulting work to help pay the bills, and I had a couple of really good years selling my software products. While it seemed like I was living the dream, I made one critical mistake. I was ignoring White Peak Software.</p>

<p>In December 2012, I finished the manuscript for the second edition of the book. It was finally time to return my focus on White Peak Software. And so here we are, the year 2013.</p>

<h2 id="start-overagain">Start Over…Again</h2>

<p>2013 has been a rough year, and I’m paying the price for ignoring White Peak Software while working on the both editions of the book. App sells are way down, and even the second edition of the book isn’t selling well. I’ve had some success this year with client work, but over all this year hasn’t gone as planned. Not only that, I’ve lost the momentum, and product revenue, that grew each year up through 2011.</p>

<p>I decided 2013 would be a reboot year for White Peak Software. It’s my third time starting over. I retired two apps at the first of the year. This action might seem sad, but it wasn’t. In fact it felt good to say bye to those apps, and it lifted a mental burden from my shoulders. Also this summer I started work on a new app, but I realized it will take me a lot of time to finish the app given its size.</p>

<p>Deciding I needed a quick win and a motivational boost, I wrote and released <a href="http://www.whitepeaksoftware.com/big-screen">Big Screen</a> a couple of weeks ago. I don’t know if Big Screen will be a hit or a dud, but it doesn’t matter. My goal with this app was to get me back into the “ship it” mindset and to remind me how great it feels to create and release my own app. Just the simple act of shipping Big Screen had already made it a success for me.</p>

<p>So that’s the 10 year history of White Peak Software. Things haven’t gone quite as planned, and there are times when I thought of calling it quits. But looking back I see I’m happier than ever working for White Peak Software. It’s been an amazing 10 years, and I’m looking forward to another 10 years.</p>

<h2 id="lessons-learned">Lessons Learned</h2>

<p>Before I go, I would like to share a few key things I have learned over the last 10 years in hopes that it will help others succeed at being an independent software developer.</p>

<ol>
  <li>
    <p>Don’t give up. There are going to be some hard times, and giving up will seem like the easy way out. Giving up is easy to do and very tempting, but as Kevin Hoctor recently said on <a href="https://alpha.app.net/kevinhoctor/post/15283389">ADN</a>, “The only true failure is giving up.”</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Learn from your mistakes. You’re going to make mistakes, and you’re going to have setbacks. But without them you will never learn. You learned to walk by first falling, and you’ll learn to succeed by making mistakes and having setbacks.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Seek feedback, advice, and opinions from others, but make your own decisions. I have found seeking the advice from other indie developers, business owners, and entrepreneurs helps me see all points of view. But at the end of the day, it’s up to me to make the decisions. If I always listened to and followed the advice from others, then I would have never created apps like Killink CSV Editor and Labor Mate. Listen to what others have to say, but make the decisions you feel are right for you.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Take chances. My second passion in life is snowboarding. One of the things I’ve learned from snowboarding is to push myself beyond my comfort zone. If I never pushed myself, I would never have discovered the joys of snowboarding. Likewise, if I didn’t take chances, if I didn’t push myself beyond my comfort zone, I would not be sitting here writing about the 10th anniversary of White Peak Software.</p>

    <p>You never know if your app will be a hit or not. This is also true for your business or whatever else it is you want to pursue. You just don’t know what will work and what will fail. But I can guarantee you instant failure if you never take a chance and try. You’ll never know if you can write a hit app if you never take the chance to write the app. You’ll never know if you can survive as an indie developer or business owner, if you never take the chance to work for yourself. Take chances and push yourself beyond your comfort zone. The worse can happen is you fail, but that’s a good thing because we learn from our failures. Taking chances and pushing yourself out of your comfort zone will make you that much better in whatever you pursue.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Define what success means to you, and don’t be swayed by others telling you their definition of success. Success means different things to different people, and one person’s definition of success might not align with your definition. For some, success means making a ton of money. For others, it is spending quality time with family. What does success mean to you?</p>
  </li>
</ol>

<p>You may have picked up on the fact that I define what success means for each of my apps and the definition isn’t necessarily the same for each app. Success doesn’t have to mean millions of downloads or thousands of dollars earned. Success can be based on what you learned, experience or how the experience motivates you to do more.</p>

<p>My definition for success with White Peak Software is to live the life I want here and now, today, and not wait for some future time after I have, quote un-quote, retired. Sure, I’m not where I thought I would be with White Peak Software after 10 years and we’re definitely not living on Easy Street with regard to our finances, but the last 10 years have still been successful. This year, for example, is the year my family and I moved to a ski town, which has been a goal of ours for years. The likelihood of this happening would have been much less if I hadn’t taken the chance of starting White Peak Software 10 years ago.</p>

<p>White Peak Software has been successful in helping me reach my goals in life, and it will continue to help me reach new goals…hopefully for at least another 10 years if not longer.</p>

<p>Happy anniversary, White Peak Software.</p>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[ANN: Big Screen Out in the Wild Early]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.whitepeaksoftware.com/2013/11/17/big-screen-out-in-the-wild-early/"/>
    <published>2013-11-17T00:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2013-11-17T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.whitepeaksoftware.com/2013/11/17/big-screen-out-in-the-wild-early</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Last night I made a <a href="https://twitter.com/kirbyt/status/401882700048781312">teaser tweet</a> about <a href="http://www.whitepeaksoftware.com/big-screen">Big Screen</a> being approved by Apple. The idea was to pique interest in the app I plan to release in a few weeks. But silly me, I forgot to set the available date to a date in the future, and soon after my tweet people were downloading Big Screen. As my friend <a href="http://www.goldenhillsoftware.com">John Brayton</a> said, I need to “think of it as extending a beta to anyone on the app store.” So with that, I’m happy to announce Big Screen is now available to everyone.</p>

<p>Big Screen is a new app for iOS that displays the camera’s video stream to any AirPlay receiver (i.e., AppleTV). What makes Big Screen different from using, say the built-in Camera app, is that Big Screen does not display any application chrome on the AirPlay receiver. This makes Big Screen ideal for presentations, conferences, and other types of gatherings where large TV monitors are used to show what’s happening on stage to the folks sitting in the back of the room.</p>

<p>There are other uses for Big Screen as well. My son, and other kids, have been using it to play a version of hide and seek. And kids in general seem to enjoy seeing themselves on TV and are finding ways to have fun with Big Screen that I never thought of. 
I should also mention that while Big Screen is free, I do have plans to hopefully make a few bucks off the app. The next update will include ads (that are displays on the device, not on the AirPlay receiver) and an In-App Purchase option to remove the ads from the app.</p>

<p>So go grab a copy of <a href="http://www.whitepeaksoftware.com/main/store/buy/big-screen">Big Screen</a>, and let me know what you think.</p>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[ANN: Learning iPad Programming, 2nd Edition, is on Sale Now]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.whitepeaksoftware.com/2013/05/28/learning-ipad-programming-on-sale-now/"/>
    <published>2013-05-28T00:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2013-05-28T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.whitepeaksoftware.com/2013/05/28/learning-ipad-programming-on-sale-now</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I’m happy to announce the second edition of <a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/0321885716/ref=as_li_ss_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;camp=1789&amp;creative=390957&amp;creativeASIN=0321885716&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;tag=whitepeaksoft-20">Learning iPad Programming</a> is now available at your favorite book store.</p>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[360intersect was Great]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.whitepeaksoftware.com/2013/04/29/360intersect-was-great/"/>
    <published>2013-04-29T00:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2013-04-29T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.whitepeaksoftware.com/2013/04/29/360intersect-was-great</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I had the pleasure of speaking at the inaugural <a href="http://www.360intersect.com">360intersect</a>, but even better I got the opportunity to attend this new, unique conference. As one attendee said to me - and I’m paraphrasing here - tech conferences are usually about professional development, but this event was more about personal development. And this was indeed the case. The speakers shared personal stories that were inspirational and highlighted the diversity of the tech community.</p>

<p>On Day 1, Victor Agreda, Jr, talked about his love for magic. Robi Ganguly talked about going from being told throughout his childhood that he cannot run to becoming an avid runner who has completed a marathon. I spoke about my Long Trail hike from last fall. And Michelle Yaiser talked about being an amateur race car driver, a musician, and dancer.</p>

<p>On Day 2, Doug McCune talked about using his love for maps and data to create art in the physical world. Jon Carroll shared stories about his love for video games, farts, and augmented reality. Josh Michaels talked about his long journey to blend his love for art and photography into a career as an app developer. And the day wrapped up with an emotional talk by Mike Lee as his reflected on his life over the past year.</p>

<p>What made all these talks great wasn’t just hearing the personal stories, but seeing how each speaker blends their various loves into what they do for a living. For instance, Robi’s talk illustrated how preparing for the marathon also prepared him to be CEO and vice versa. Michelle related race car driving to how one should to approach work and focus. Josh said don’t wait, pursue your dreams now. And I said don’t work so hard.</p>

<p>The turnout for this first 360intersect was small, but that was expected. Personally I think the size was perfect because it gave everyone an opportunity to meet and chat with one another. And it made it possible to have group activities such as the duck boat tour of Seattle, the Saturday night dinner at Pike Brewing Company, and the straggler’s dinner at Mama’s on Sunday.</p>

<p>I thoroughly enjoyed the outstanding talks, the cool venture, seeing old friend, and making new ones. And I’m already looking forward to the next 360intersect. Big thanks goes out to John and Nicole for putting on this great event.</p>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[ANN: Product Retirements]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.whitepeaksoftware.com/2013/01/02/ann-product-retirement/"/>
    <published>2013-01-02T00:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2013-01-02T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.whitepeaksoftware.com/2013/01/02/ann-product-retirement</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>It’s a brand new year, and as the saying goes, out with the old and in with the new.</p>

<p>I mentioned in my <a href="/2012/12/29/year-in-review/">2012 Year in Review</a> post that I’m re-focusing my intention on White Peak Software this year. In some was this re-focus is like a re-boot for WPS. This means exciting new things for the company going forward, but it also means it’s time to good bye a couple of products.</p>

<p>The first product retiring is SMTP Diagnostics. SMTP Diagnostics was White Peak Software’s very first product. I honestly did not know if the app would sell or not, nor did I care. I released it because, at the time, it was an app I needed and used regularly. The release of SMTP Diagnostics also gave me the opportunity to learn how to sell software online. Without SMTP Diagnostics, I would not have been as prepared for the other White Peak Software apps.</p>

<p>The second product retiring today is Hey Peanut. Hey Peanut was written for my son Rowan, who was only one and a half at the time. I had high hopes for Hey Peanut. My son loved the app, and I thought other kids would enjoy it as well. I invested time and money into the app, but unfortunately I missed the mark with it. All is not lost though. I learned a lot from the mistakes I made with Hey Peanut that will help me going forward.</p>

<p>It saddens me to see these two apps removed from the White Peak Software home page. Both are very special to me in their own ways. But it is a new year, so out with the old and in with the new.</p>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[2012 Year in Review]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.whitepeaksoftware.com/2012/12/29/year-in-review/"/>
    <published>2012-12-29T00:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2012-12-29T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.whitepeaksoftware.com/2012/12/29/year-in-review</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Three years ago I wrote my first, and last, <a href="http://blog.whitepeaksoftware.com/2009/12/30/white-peak-software-year-in-review-2009/">year in review</a> for White Peak Software. I had hoped I would continue doing a year in review each year, but life, and the <a href="http://www.learningipadprogramming.com">book</a>, got in the way. A lot has happened in the last three years, but I want to focus on this last year, 2012.</p>

<p>I’ve been disappointed throughout most of 2012, but looking back, I’m not sure why. Overall it’s been a good year, and I realized I have accomplished quite a bit in very little time. But since starting on the book back in mid-2010, I have felt like I can’t deliver, missing one milestone after another after another. And this is why I have felt disappointed throughout 2012.</p>

<h1 id="a-quick-look-back">A Quick Look Back</h1>

<p>I started writing <a href="http://www.learningipadprogramming.com">Learning iPad Programming</a> in May 2010. My original goal was to have the manuscript complete by November 2010, a lofty goal for a first time writer. The manuscript, which was more than 700 pages, was completed in September 2011, nearly a year late. I sunk into a depression over the delays in finishing the book, which of course led to more delays. I stopped work on all other projects so I could focus on the book, but it didn’t really help. If not for <a href="https://twitter.com/atomicbird">Tom Harrington</a>, who agreed to co-author the book with me in June 2011, I don’t think I would have ever finished the book.</p>

<p>Working with Tom gave me the motivation I needed to crank out chapters from June through the beginning of September, and crank out chapters we did, writing over fifty percent of the book during that time.</p>

<p>The book was finally published in December 2011, and I planned to return my focus on White Peak Software. But I was once again distracted, this time by a <a href="http://my.safaribooksonline.com/9780132981163">video project</a> related to the book.</p>

<p>A week before the book was available in bookstores, I went to Chicago to record the <a href="http://my.safaribooksonline.com/9780132981163">Learning iPad Programming LiveLessons</a>, a training video based on the book. Like writing the book, this was the first time I had ever done anything like this, and I was ill prepared. I thought I would knock out the recording in a couple of days, but that didn’t happen. But unlike the book, I didn’t have months and months to record. I had to finish the project by the end of the week. This meant very little sleep for me each night as I re-thought and re-worked the topics that I planned to cover the following day. I left Chicago completely exhausted, but I was very happy with what had been accomplished.</p>

<p>At this point I had basically ignored White Peak Software for over a year and a half. Not good for business. Product sales had declined by nearly fifty percent, and we were cash poor (“we” being my family and me). I took on a client project in October 2011, which shipped February 2012. The project was suppose to help us with cash, but the project was for a startup that had its own cash problems. The project ended up hurt us more than helping us.</p>

<h1 id="in-tough-time-go-snowboarding">In Tough Time, Go Snowboarding</h1>

<p>Despite the struggles, the family and I packed our bags and headed to Killington, VT, for a month. We were broke, but living the dream getting to ski and snowboard almost daily. Unfortunately it was one of the worse winter seasons in recorded history for Killington, which meant there was very little snow. On the plus side, the temperatures were warmer than expected, which was perfect for Rowan, age 3 at the time, to learn how to ski.</p>

<p>Returning from Killington, I took on one more book related project. As the saying goes, “Fool me once, shame on you. Fool me twice, shame on me.” I guess I was in the need of more personal shame.</p>

<p>I needed cash, and I needed to focus on the business, but I, shamefully, decided to do one more book related project, an enhanced epub version of the book. The enhanced epub version would include audio and video to enhance the book’s content. I had produced over four and a half hours of edited video and audio by the time I finished my part of the project. Unfortunately the enhanced epub book never happened due to production problems by the publisher.</p>

<p>To help with cash, I took on a few short (40 hours or less) client projects. But even better was the first royalty check for the book. Turns out the book is a hit, and while I went broke writing it, I was very happy to finally see some money coming in from that effort. Granted the book hasn’t earned me a lot of money, but I have been able to pay some bills with the two royalty checks I’ve received so far. (Thank you, readers!)</p>

<p>This encouraged me to do a second edition of the book. Yes, fool me a fourth time. Instead of focusing on my business and getting back on track, I decided to do more writing. But first, I needed a break.</p>

<h1 id="take-a-hike">Take a Hike</h1>

<p>I decided to take a month off from everything and attempt a thru hike of the Long Trail in Vermont. The Long Trail is a 272 mile hiking trail that starts at the Canadian border and runs the length of Vermont to the Massachusetts border. I disconnected from the world and set off on a <a href="http://www.thecave.com/2012/09/25/back-from-the-long-trail-hike/">four week journey</a>. Unfortunately I injured my knee and had to stop after two weeks of hiking and covering nearly 100 miles.</p>

<p>I returned from the hike with new energy and motivation (and a lot of pain in my left knee). I also came back with a different outlook on life and business. I realized I shouldn’t be disappointed about what I perceived as a lack of accomplishment and failure. Instead I realized that despite how much it seems like I’m working and un-delivering, I’m actually enjoying life at lot more.</p>

<h1 id="accomplishments">Accomplishments</h1>

<p>The disappointment I felt over much of 2012, as well as in 2010 and 2011, was caused by the transition I was going through, a transition from being a workaholic to a successful slacker. I felt disappointed about the last year, feeling like I can’t deliver. But here is the list of what I’ve done since December 2011:</p>

<ul>
  <li>Published a book (yes, the book was written before December 2011, but the fact that it was actually published and made available in bookstores across the country gave me a huge sense of accomplishment, bigger than finishing the manuscript).</li>
  <li>Recorded and published an 8-hour training video.</li>
  <li>Recorded 4.5 hours of audio and video for an enhanced epub.</li>
  <li>Shipped a client app.</li>
  <li>Completed multiple small client projects.</li>
  <li>Wrote an article on <a href="http://www.informit.com/articles/article.aspx?p=1914191">Xcode code snippets</a>.</li>
  <li>Released two updates to <a href="http://www.whitepeaksoftware.com/main/labor-mate/index">Labor Mate</a></li>
  <li>Spent a month living in a ski town.</li>
  <li>Spent 2 weeks hiking the Long Trail, followed by two more weeks of traveling for fun.</li>
  <li>Completed the second edition of <a href="http://www.learningipadprogramming.com">Learning iPad Programming</a></li>
  <li>Re-wrote <a href="http://www.photowheelapp.com">PhotoWheel</a> for iOS 6.</li>
</ul>

<p>And I’m a few weeks away from shipping another client app. I’ve also been hosting a monthly happy hour for Mac and iOS developers called <a href="http://www.nshappyhour.org">NSHappyHour</a>, and I co-organize the CocoaHeads Boston monthly meeting.</p>

<p>I look at this list, and I think, “Wow! What a great set of accomplishments.” Others have done more, a lot more, and this is where I start to feel disappointed. The workaholic in me wants to accomplishment more, but then I remind myself this one interesting little fact. I have tracked a total of 1,293.75 hours for 2012 in <a href="http://www.getharvest.com">Harvest</a>.</p>

<p>Based on a 50-work week year (giving 2 weeks off for vacation), the 1,293.75 hours comes out to a weekly average of 25.88 hours. That means I’m working just under 26 hours a week on average. Granted, that’s not what is really happening. Instead I have weeks were I work 50 hours or more, but I also have weeks where I work no hours at all. Also the list above includes the video I recorded in Chicago, but the time recording the video was not logged in 2012. The 1,293.75 hours is for time logged in 2012, but my accomplishment list covers 13 months. Still, I list it here because the video was released in February 2012.</p>

<p>Also, there are times when I answer support email, a minute here and there, that I don’t log to my time sheet. So maybe there is an additional 20 to 40 hours not represented in my 2012 timesheet. Still, keeping in mind the amount of hours I devoted to work related activities, which is low compared to most, I don’t feel as disappointed when I look back over the last year. I feel like I have accomplished quite a bit while only working part-time. I’m well on my way to becoming a successful slacker, as I like to call it.</p>

<h1 id="whats-next">What’s Next?</h1>

<p>So this brings me to the end of 2012, a year that had me feeling disappointed through most of it only to realize I don’t have anything to be disappointed about. Well, that’s not exactly true. While I’m happy with my accomplishments over the last year, I am still disappointed that I have ignored White Peak Software for most of the year. So that’s what’s next for me…a returned focus on White Peak Software in 2013. This mean some changes to existing products - some good, some bad depending on your point of view. It also means some new products. But most importantly, it means I return to my number one passion, writing code.</p>

<p>I’m looking forward to seeing what I’m able to accomplish in 2013 while maintaining my status as a successful slacker.</p>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[ANN: Office is Open]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.whitepeaksoftware.com/2012/09/10/office-is-open/"/>
    <published>2012-09-10T00:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2012-09-10T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.whitepeaksoftware.com/2012/09/10/office-is-open</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The White Peak Software office is once again open. It’s back to business as usual.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[ANN: Office Closed August 22 Through End of September]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.whitepeaksoftware.com/2012/08/20/office-closed/"/>
    <published>2012-08-20T00:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2012-08-20T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.whitepeaksoftware.com/2012/08/20/office-closed</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The White Peak Software office will be closed from Wednesday, August 22, through the end of September.</p>

<p>I am leaving for a month long backpacking trip starting on August 22, and I plan to return by the end of September. Unfortunately I will not have Internet access during this trip, which is why the office will be closed. I apologize in advance for any inconvenience this might cause.</p>

<p>All support emails will be answered in the order they are received once I return.</p>

<p>If you have lost your license information and need it re-sent, click <a href="http://www.whitepeaksoftware.com/support/licenselookup">here</a> and provide the email address used when the order was placed. Your license information will be retrieved and sent to you via email.</p>

<p>An update to this blog will be posted as soon as the White Peak Software office returned to normal operations.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Prolonging My Laptop's Battery with FruitJuice]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.whitepeaksoftware.com/2012/08/14/Prolonging-My-Laptops-Battery-with-FruitJuice/"/>
    <published>2012-08-14T00:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2012-08-14T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.whitepeaksoftware.com/2012/08/14/Prolonging-My-Laptops-Battery-with-FruitJuice</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>For more than 10 years my primary dev machines have been laptops. The mobility provided by a laptop has changed the way, and where, I work. However, an unfortunate downside of me using a laptop as my primary machine is the number of batteries I go through. On average a laptop battery will last me about a year before I need to order a replacement. It’s common for battery life to degrade some after a year, but for me it’s common to see “Service Battery” around the 1-year mark.</p>

<p>Why do I burn through so many laptop batteries? It’s the way I use my laptop.</p>

<p>I often times treat my laptop as a desktop leaving it plugged into power for days, and sometimes even weeks at a time. But laptops are not designed for this kind of usage. The battery, like a muscle in your body, needs to be exercised. For a lithium-ion battery - found in most if not all laptops today - this means <a href="http://www.ehow.com/how_7259005_condition-laptop-battery.html">conditioning the battery</a>.</p>

<p>To condition a battery, you need to regularly run your laptop on battery power using only a portion of the battery’s power, and then charge the battery as often as possible before the battery fully discharges. After about 30 charge cycles you want to do a full discharge of the battery followed by a full recharge.</p>

<p>Whew! That’s a lot of work to exercise a laptop battery. Well okay, it’s not a lot of work, but it does require some discipline. And history has proven I don’t have the discipline to properly condition my laptop’s battery.</p>

<p>So now I’m faced with a dilemma. I have a shinny, new MacBook Pro that doesn’t have a swappable battery. The battery can be replaced, but it must be replaced by Apple. I can’t simply buy a replacement battery online and pop it in when I need it. So I’m trying to change my ways to prolong the battery life for my new MacBook Pro, and I’m using <a href="http://fruitjuiceapp.com">FruitJuice</a> to help me along the way.</p>

<p><a href="http://fruitjuiceapp.com">FruitJuice</a> is a combination Mac app and web service that helps extend the life of your laptop’s battery by guiding you through the battery conditioning steps. It works by not only reminding you to condition your battery, it steps you through the conditioning process with convention and helpful email and SMS notifications. And when you are between conditioning periods, you can use FruitJuice to see how well you are exercising your battery by alternating between running on battery power and charging the battery.</p>

<p><img src="/images/blog/2012-08-14-FruitJuice.png" alt="" /></p>

<p>It’s this last feature that I like the most. I find myself checking my plugged in percentage a few times a day to make sure I stay in the green zone.  The green zone is the ideal combination of running on battery power and plugged into a power source. Hopefully a future version of FruitJuice will notify me when I’ve been out of the green zone for too long, reminding me to unplug and run off the battery. But until such feature exists, I’ll keep an eye on my plugged in percentage.</p>

<p>Using FruitJuice comes with another benefit. It keeps a complete history of battery usage and conditioning. This information can be useful when it’s time to ask Apple for a replacement battery, should you need to prove you have been operating your laptop based on <a href="http://www.apple.com/batteries/notebooks.html">Apple’s own recommended usage and maintenance</a>.</p>

<p>FruitJuice comes with a free 30-day trial, and cost $9.99 per year for one computer. Each additional computer costs $4.99 per year. This is cheap when you compare it to the cost of a new battery, which costs me $129 the last time I bought one for my older MacBook Pro.</p>

<p>So is FruitJuice saving me money? It’s too early to tell since my MacBook Pro is only a couple of weeks old. But I’m hopeful that a year from now I will not see the dreaded “Service Battery” condition that I’ve seen over and over the past few years.</p>

<p>Disclaimer: I was not asked or paid to do this review. I was an early beta tester for FruitJuice, and I continue to be a FruitJuice user.</p>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[First Impressions: MacBook Pro with Retina Display]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.whitepeaksoftware.com/2012/07/31/first-impressions-macbook-pro-with-retina-display/"/>
    <published>2012-07-31T00:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2012-07-31T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.whitepeaksoftware.com/2012/07/31/first-impressions-macbook-pro-with-retina-display</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>In July 2007 I bought a fully loaded MacBook Pro. It was by far the best computer I have ever owned. And that isn’t just my opinion. PC World said the Apple MacBook Pro was the <a href="http://www.pcworld.com/article/136649-3/in_pictures_the_most_notable_notebooks_of_2007.html">fastest Windows Vista notebook</a> at the time.</p>

<p>My MacBook Pro was also the most expensive computer I have ever bought. The high price tag wasn’t because of the perceived “Mac tax.” The high price tag was due to hardware cost. In fact, I looked at what it would cost to buy the same set of hardware from Dell at the time, and Dell’s price was $200 more than Apple’s.</p>

<p>My MacBook Pro has served me well for 5 years, which is a long time especially for a laptop. But it has reached its limits. The machine, while still usable, is just too slow for the work I do daily. I might be able to squeeze out another year if I could bump up the RAM to 8 GB or even 16 GB, but sadly, that model only goes to 4 GB. (Yes, I know there is a non-Apple recommended way to bump up to 6 GB, but let’s face it. Five years is a long time for a laptop.) So nearly 5 years to the date, I got myself a new MacBook Pro. (My previous MBP arrived July 25, 2007, and my latest one arrived July 30, 3012.)</p>

<p>It’s too early to say if I will get 5 years of service out of this latest MBP, but I’m hopeful I will. And while my latest MBP is expensive, it still costed less than the one I bought in 2007 - by nearly $700 if I remember correctly. Though admittedly I did not get the maxed out MBP this time around. I got the 2.6 GHz Intel Core i7 with 16 GB RAM, 512 GB flash storage, and retina display.</p>

<p>My first impression of the new MacBook Pro: It’s a sweet machine.</p>

<p>It feels heavier than I expected, but it’s still lighter than my 2007 MBP. It’s super quiet especially compared to my 2007 MBP. My 2007 MBP’s fan runs non-stop when attached to the power cord. This started when I updated to Lion and has annoyed me ever since. (Thankfully my Bose noise canceling headphones drown out the fan noise from my old MBP.) And my new MBP doesn’t heat up like my old one does.</p>

<p>My new MBP is fast, really fast compared to my 2007 MBP. This is most noticeable for me when compiling projects in Xcode. A project that would take a minute and a half to do a clean compile now takes 10 seconds. And iPhoto, with my 40 GB library, is once again useable. iPhoto was so painfully slow on my other MBP that I only used it to import photos and that was it. But last night I was tagging faces, looking at photos from places, and doing some minor cropping and editing on my shinny, new MBP.</p>

<p>While I knew the new MBP would be faster, lighter, and better than my previous MBP, the one feature I was lukewarm on is the retina display. If the non-retina MBP supported 16 GB of RAM then I might have bought one of them instead of the retina MBP. However, after using my new MBP for a day, I so glad I went with the retina display. Text on the new retina display is crisp, clear, and much more readable than on the non-retina display. And as someone who has to stare at text all day, this was a welcome surprise for me. I was indifferent about the retina display before buying my MBP, but now, I can’t imaging buy a new MBP without the retina display.</p>

<p>The retina display also provides one additional benefit for me. I’m currently working on the second addition of my book <a href="http://amzn.to/ipadprogbook">Learning iPad Programming</a>. My publisher prefers screenshots for figure images to be at 150 ppi minimum, but normal computer displays are only 72 ppi. With the new retina display, I can take screenshots that are 144 ppi. Still not quite 150 ppi, but a lot closer, which should make my publisher happier.</p>

<p>So after only a day of playing on the new MBP with retina display, was the purchase worth well for me? Absolutely. There’s no doubt in my mind that going with the MBP with retina display was the right choice for me. That said, if my previous MBP were only a year or so old, I might have held off on the purchase until the price drops a bit. But for me, at this time, the new MBP with retina display is the idea machine for me. The 16 GB of RAM, faster CPU and flash storage, and of course the retina display are vast improvements needed for my daily work.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Wanted: Beta Testers for Killink CSV Editor]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.whitepeaksoftware.com/2011/06/28/wanted-beta-testers-for-killink-csv-editor/"/>
    <published>2011-06-28T00:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2011-06-28T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.whitepeaksoftware.com/2011/06/28/wanted-beta-testers-for-killink-csv-editor</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I posted a new beta for Killink CSV Editor v2 today. The big feature added to version 2 is Unicode support. This means Killink CSV Editor can now read and write not only ASCII files but UTF-8 and UTF-16 files.</p>

<p>If you’re a Killink CSV Editor user and you want to live life on the edge, please <a href="http://cdn.whitepeaksoftware.com/downloads/setup-killinkcsv-250.exe">download beta 2</a>, give it a test drive, and send email to <em>support at white peak software dot com</em> if you encounter any issues. Note this build of Killink CSV Editor installs, by default, in a separate directory allowing both Version 1.14 and Version 2.0 to co-exists on the same computer.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Great Time at VTM]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.whitepeaksoftware.com/2011/04/11/great-time-at-vtm/"/>
    <published>2011-04-11T00:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2011-04-11T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.whitepeaksoftware.com/2011/04/11/great-time-at-vtm</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This weekend was <a href="http://voicesthatmatter.com/">Voices That Matter</a> Seattle. It was my second time attending VTM and second time speaking. I have to say this latest installment of VTM was even better than the last one in Philly.</p>

<p>My conference weekend kicked off on Friday with a full day workshop learning <a href="http://www.cocos2d-iphone.org/">Cocos2D</a>. This workshop was full of juicy awesome goodness, and for the first time in my career I feel like I now know how to write a game. In fact I have a new game idea brewing in my head as I type this. <a href="http://twitter.com/rodstrougo">Rod Strougo</a> and <a href="http://twitter.com/rwenderlich">Ray Wenderlich</a> did an outstanding job putting together and teaching the full day workshop.</p>

<p>VTM continued to impress for the next two days. Some highlights for me included:</p>

<ul>
  <li>
    <p><a href="http://twitter.com/bmf">Mike Lee’s</a> keynote. I was especially moved by the part where Mike talked about our wonderful iOS and Mac developer community.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Hearing <a href="http://twitter.com/zaphodgjd">Graeme Devine</a> talk on Game Center and the Art of Addictive Games and getting to meet him. We had some good chats. It wasn’t until later I found out <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Graeme_Devine">who he really is</a>.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Meeting <a href="http://www.kevincallahan.org/">Kevin Callahan</a> and getting the one-on-one demo of <a href="http://www.kevincallahan.org/software/accessorizer.html">Accessorizer</a>. This app is awesome and does so much to make you more productive in Xcode.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>And of course catching up with old friends and making new ones (too many to list here).</p>
  </li>
</ul>

<p>Thanks to the <a href="http://twitter.com/vtm_iphone">VTM organizers</a> for putting on a great event, and special thanks to <a href="http://twitter.com/chuckdude">Chuck</a> for getting me from and to the airport.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
