<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: cross post | White Peak Software Blog]]></title>
  <link href="http://blog.whitepeaksoftware.com/category/cross post/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://blog.whitepeaksoftware.com/"/>
  <updated>2017-01-28T09:51:31-05:00</updated>
  <id>http://blog.whitepeaksoftware.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Kirby Turner]]></name>
    
  </author>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Quickly Post Photos To Facebook]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.whitepeaksoftware.com/2015/03/25/quickly-post-photos-to-facebook/"/>
    <updated>2015-03-25T07:40:55-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.whitepeaksoftware.com/2015/03/25/quickly-post-photos-to-facebook</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Last night a friend of mine was trying to post photos to Facebook. We were at <a href="http://www.stowecider.com">Stowe Cider</a> for their Cider House Rules event, which, by the way, was a lot of fun. Unfortunately for my friend the Facebook app was slow to load and it crashed a few times on her iPhone. The slow Internet connection was the likely cause of the problem, but even if the Internet connection had been better, my friend would still have to wait for the Facebook app to do its thing before she could post the photos. That’s when I showed her my app, <a href="http://www.whitepeaksoftware.com/cross-post">Cross Post</a>.</p>

<p>Cross Post sends your post to Facebook and Twitter. It doesn’t download your timeline or stream, so you don’t have to worry about the app taking a long time to load. But there is another feature of Cross Post that makes it even easier and faster to share photos: the share extension.</p>

<p>With the Cross Post share extension, you can access Cross Post from virtual any app on your iPhone and iPad. As an example I showed my friend how easy it is to share a new photo from the Camera app. I took a picture. I tapped the picture thumbnail in the lower left corner of the Camera app screen. I tapped the Share icon - that’s the one of a rectangle with an up arrow coming out of the top. I tapped the Cross Post icon, typed in a message, selected Facebook, and sent off the picture for my friends on Facebook to enjoy.</p>

<p>It sounds like a lot of steps when you write it out like that, but it really isn’t as you can see in this short <a href="https://vimeo.com/123186958">video</a>.</p>

<p><div class="vimeo-video"><figure><iframe src="//player.vimeo.com/video/123186958" width="500" height="281" frameborder="0" webkitallowfullscreen mozallowfullscreen allowfullscreen></iframe></figure></div></p>

<p>The share extension isn’t limited to sharing photos either. You can use it to share links and text from other apps as well.</p>

<p>Wanna try Cross Post for free? Just <a href="https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/cross-post/id872543786?mt=8&amp;uo=4&amp;at=11lcj9&amp;ct=blog">download it</a> from the App Store.</p>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[ANN: Cross Post v1.2 is in the App Store]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.whitepeaksoftware.com/2014/12/13/ann-cross-post-v1-2-is-in-the-app-store/"/>
    <updated>2014-12-13T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.whitepeaksoftware.com/2014/12/13/ann-cross-post-v1-2-is-in-the-app-store</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The latest update to Cross Post has hit the App Store. This update fixes bugs and adds new features including:</p>

<ul>
  <li>A photo album picker.</li>
  <li>An option to attach the last photo taken.</li>
  <li>Smart quotes and punctuations.</li>
  <li><em>wpscrosspost</em> URL scheme for Launch Center Pro support</li>
</ul>

<p><a href="https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/cross-post/id872543786?mt=8&amp;uo=4&amp;at=11lcj9&amp;ct=blog">Download Cross Post</a> from the App Store now.</p>

<h2 id="smart-quotes">Smart Quotes</h2>

<p>To turn on smart quotes and punctuations, tap the post composer and select <strong>Use Smart Quotes</strong> in the edit menu. Select <strong>Use Dumb Quotes</strong> to turn it off.</p>

<p><img src="https://farm8.staticflickr.com/7524/15392871453_65c9d32fd2.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<h2 id="url-scheme">URL Scheme</h2>

<p><strong>wpscrosspost</strong> has been added as the custom URL scheme for Cross Post. You can use it to launch Cross Post from other apps. There is also a compose action that lets you set the post text and even attach the last photo.</p>

<p>To launch Cross Post, use the URL:</p>

<p><strong>wpscrosspost://</strong></p>

<p>To compose a new post, use:</p>

<p><strong>wpscrosspost://compose?text=[text]&amp;attachment=photo:last</strong></p>

<p>Both parameters are optional. The parameter <em>text</em> can be any text that you want to include in the post. The parameter <em>attachment</em> lets you attach a photo to the post. At the moment <strong>photo:last</strong> is the only supported value for <em>attachment</em> parameter.</p>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[ANN: Cross Post, Sharing Across Social Sites Made Simple]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.whitepeaksoftware.com/2014/11/20/ann-cross-post-sharing-across-social-sites-made-simple/"/>
    <updated>2014-11-20T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.whitepeaksoftware.com/2014/11/20/ann-cross-post-sharing-across-social-sites-made-simple</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="http://257bf79813094f196f16-bc6ead213ec900841fcf0484ae93cd9e.r62.cf2.rackcdn.com/images/cross-post/crosspost-screenshot.png" alt="image" height="200px" style="float: left; margin: 0 1em 1em 0;" /> I am thrilled to announce the release of <a href="http://www.whitepeaksoftware.com/cross-post">Cross Post</a>, a new app for iPhone and iPad that makes it simple to share your post, photos, and links to Facebook, Twitter, and App.net. I talk in detail <a href="http://www.thecave.com/2014/09/14/cross-posting-to-app.net-facebook-and-twitter/">why I decided to write Cross Post</a> over on my personal blog site, but long story short, I wanted a better way to share my thoughts and photos across different social media sites. And <a href="http://www.whitepeaksoftware.com/cross-post">Cross Post</a> is that better way.</p>

<p>Cross Post is free to download and use, but it has limits. You can post to only one social media site at a time using the free version. This gives you a chance to try out Cross Post without spending a cent. If you decide Cross Post is right for you and you want to post to multiple social media sites at the same time, then unlock everything the app has to offer for just $2.99.</p>

<p>What are you waiting for? <a href="https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/cross-post/id872543786?mt=8&amp;uo=4&amp;at=11lcj9&amp;ct=blog">Download Cross Post</a> from the App Store now.</p>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
