<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: smtp diagnostics | White Peak Software Blog]]></title>
  <link href="http://blog.whitepeaksoftware.com/category/smtp diagnostics/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://blog.whitepeaksoftware.com/"/>
  <updated>2015-04-20T09:59:49-04:00</updated>
  <id>http://blog.whitepeaksoftware.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Kirby Turner]]></name>
    
  </author>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[ANN: Product Retirements]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.whitepeaksoftware.com/2013/01/02/ann-product-retirement/"/>
    <updated>2013-01-02T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.whitepeaksoftware.com/2013/01/02/ann-product-retirement</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>It’s a brand new year, and as the saying goes, out with the old and in with the new. </p>

<p>I mentioned in my <a href="/2012/12/29/year-in-review/">2012 Year in Review</a> post that I’m re-focusing my intention on White Peak Software this year. In some was this re-focus is like a re-boot for WPS. This means exciting new things for the company going forward, but it also means it’s time to good bye a couple of products.</p>

<p>The first product retiring is SMTP Diagnostics. SMTP Diagnostics was White Peak Software’s very first product. I honestly did not know if the app would sell or not, nor did I care. I released it because, at the time, it was an app I needed and used regularly. The release of SMTP Diagnostics also gave me the opportunity to learn how to sell software online. Without SMTP Diagnostics, I would not have been as prepared for the other White Peak Software apps.</p>

<p>The second product retiring today is Hey Peanut. Hey Peanut was written for my son Rowan, who was only one and a half at the time. I had high hopes for Hey Peanut. My son loved the app, and I thought other kids would enjoy it as well. I invested time and money into the app, but unfortunately I missed the mark with it. All is not lost though. I learned a lot from the mistakes I made with Hey Peanut that will help me going forward.</p>

<p>It saddens me to see these two apps removed from the White Peak Software home page. Both are very special to me in their own ways. But it is a new year, so out with the old and in with the new.</p>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
