<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: announcements | White Peak Software Blog]]></title>
  <link href="http://blog.whitepeaksoftware.com/category/announcements/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://blog.whitepeaksoftware.com/"/>
  <updated>2016-01-01T21:17:29-05:00</updated>
  <id>http://blog.whitepeaksoftware.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Kirby Turner]]></name>
    
  </author>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Special Offer For Killink CSV Editor Customers]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.whitepeaksoftware.com/2015/11/20/special-offer-for-killink-csv-editor-customers/"/>
    <updated>2015-11-20T11:47:27-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.whitepeaksoftware.com/2015/11/20/special-offer-for-killink-csv-editor-customers</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I recently made the tough decision to <a href="http://blog.whitepeaksoftware.com/2015/08/18/killinks-retirement/">retire</a> Killink CSV Editor. This retirement means new licenses for the CSV editor are no longer available for purchase.</p>

<h2 id="but-what-does-this-mean-for-existing-killink-csv-editor-customers">But what does this mean for existing Killink CSV Editor customers?</h2>

<p>Nothing changes. If you previously purchased a Killink CSV Editor license, then you can continue using the editor. And I’m available to answer any questions you might have about the editor.</p>

<p>I do understand some of you may prefer using a CSV editor that is gaining new features and improvements. That’s why I’m happy to share with you a nice offer from the makers of <a href="http://www.ronsplace.eu/Products/RonsEditor">Ron’s Editor</a>, another outstanding CSV editor for Windows.</p>

<h2 id="free-rons-editor-license">Free Ron’s Editor License</h2>

<p>Existing Killink CSV Editor customer are eligible to receive a FREE license to Ron’s Editor. Claiming the free license is easy as 1-2-3.</p>

<ol>
  <li>
    <p>Visit: <a href="https://www.ronsplace.eu/Products/RonsEditor/Partner/WhitePeak?utm_source=white-peak-software-blog&amp;utm_medium=website&amp;utm_campaign=ron-s-editor-offer-to-killink-csv-editor-users">https://www.ronsplace.eu/Products/RonsEditor/Partner/WhitePeak</a></p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Enter your Killink CSV Editor license key, then click Find. (<a href="http://www.whitepeaksoftware.com/licenselookup/">Lost your license?</a>)</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Enter your name and email address, then click Send.</p>
  </li>
</ol>

<p>That’s it. You will receive an email containing your new license key for Ron’s Editor.</p>

<p>To learn more about Ron’s Editor, the Ultimate CSV Editor, visit their <a href="http://www.ronsplace.eu/Products/RonsEditor">website</a>. You can also download a trial version of the editor if you want to try it out before taking advantage of this offer.</p>

<p>To learn more about why I decided to retire Killink CSV Editor, read this <a href="http://blog.whitepeaksoftware.com/2015/08/18/killinks-retirement/">post</a>.</p>

<h2 id="thank-you">Thank You</h2>

<p>Finally, to Killink CSV Editor customers, thank you for your understanding with this tough decision. And thank you for your support of Killink CSV Editor over the years. It’s individuals like you that keep small businesses like mine running.</p>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[ANN: Killink's Retirement]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.whitepeaksoftware.com/2015/08/18/killinks-retirement/"/>
    <updated>2015-08-18T11:03:48-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.whitepeaksoftware.com/2015/08/18/killinks-retirement</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The time has come to retire Killink CVS Editor. This is not an easy decision for me to make. But with the recent release of Windows 10 and the lack of active development work going into Killink, I feel it is time.</p>

<p>A big part of me hates to see this product come to an end. It is a great app and many people rely on it daily. I tried multiple times over the years to find a new home for Killink, but I didn’t have any luck.</p>

<p>Sales of Killink have slowly dropped over the years as well, and rightfully so. I’ve not actively worked on the app in the while nor have I actively marketed the app.</p>

<p>The combination of falling sales, the lack of active development, the release of a new version of Windows and the unsuccessful attempts to find a new home for Killink CSV Editor have all led to my decision to retire it.</p>

<p><strong>What does this retirement mean for current users of Killink CSV Editor?</strong></p>

<p>For the loyal customers who bought a Killink CSV Editor license, nothing changes. You can continue using the app.(<sup id="fnref:1"><a href="#fn:1" class="footnote">1</a></sup>) This includes installing and using the app on new computers. And I will continue providing support for the app by answering your questions and helping you if you happen to encounter a problem using the app.</p>

<p>Nothing changes for the licensed user, but for those without a license, well, I’m sorry to say you can no longer purchase a license. As part of this retirement, new licenses are no longer available for purchase.</p>

<p>I know this decision to stop selling new licenses will disappoint some folks, and I full expect to receive some angry emails over the next few months. All I can say is I’m sorry.</p>

<p><strong>Why not make the app free?</strong></p>

<p>I thought about offering Killink as a free app, but I feel this would be a metaphoric slap in the face to those who paid for the software. Plus, I’m still providing support to those customers who already bought a license.</p>

<p>Making the app free to everyone would mean I have to also offer support to non-paying customers as there is no easy way for me to distinguish between those who paid and those who didn’t. Or the alternative would be ending support all together just so others can use the software for free, but that isn’t fair either to the folks who paid for the software. So Killink will not be re-released as a free app.</p>

<p>To those who have purchase Killink CSV Editor and continue to use it today, I thank you for your support over the years. And please know that even though new licenses can no longer be purchased, you can continue using your license and the software for as long as you like.(<sup id="fnref:1:1"><a href="#fn:1" class="footnote">1</a></sup>)</p>

<hr />

<div class="footnotes">
  <ol>
    <li id="fn:1">
      <p>If you have a paid license, you can continue using Killink CSV Editor well into the future as long as the version of Windows you are using supports running older software. Best efforts will be made to offer continuous support on newer versions of Windows, but there is no guarantee the software will run on future versions of Windows. <a href="#fnref:1" class="reversefootnote">&#8617;</a> <a href="#fnref:1:1" class="reversefootnote">&#8617;<sup>2</sup></a></p>
    </li>
  </ol>
</div>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[ANN: Peak App Care]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.whitepeaksoftware.com/2015/08/13/ann-peak-app-care/"/>
    <updated>2015-08-13T09:35:25-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.whitepeaksoftware.com/2015/08/13/ann-peak-app-care</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I’m excited to announce a new service from White Peak Software called <a href="https://www.peakappcare.com">Peak App Care</a>. Peak App Care is a monthly subscription service for maintaining your iOS apps. What do I mean by that? Simply put, we monitor your app for crashes and fix them as quickly as possible. Not only that, we perform small jobs such as bug fixes and enhancements to your app at your request, and we even manage the App Store for you, from updating screenshots to submitting new builds on your behalf.</p>

<p>To Learn more about this new service, visit the new <a href="https://www.peakappcare.com">Peak App Care website</a>.</p>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[ANN: Cross Post v1.2 is in the App Store]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.whitepeaksoftware.com/2014/12/13/ann-cross-post-v1-2-is-in-the-app-store/"/>
    <updated>2014-12-13T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.whitepeaksoftware.com/2014/12/13/ann-cross-post-v1-2-is-in-the-app-store</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The latest update to Cross Post has hit the App Store. This update fixes bugs and adds new features including:</p>

<ul>
  <li>A photo album picker.</li>
  <li>An option to attach the last photo taken.</li>
  <li>Smart quotes and punctuations.</li>
  <li><em>wpscrosspost</em> URL scheme for Launch Center Pro support</li>
</ul>

<p><a href="https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/cross-post/id872543786?mt=8&amp;uo=4&amp;at=11lcj9&amp;ct=blog">Download Cross Post</a> from the App Store now.</p>

<h2 id="smart-quotes">Smart Quotes</h2>

<p>To turn on smart quotes and punctuations, tap the post composer and select <strong>Use Smart Quotes</strong> in the edit menu. Select <strong>Use Dumb Quotes</strong> to turn it off.</p>

<p><img src="https://farm8.staticflickr.com/7524/15392871453_65c9d32fd2.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<h2 id="url-scheme">URL Scheme</h2>

<p><strong>wpscrosspost</strong> has been added as the custom URL scheme for Cross Post. You can use it to launch Cross Post from other apps. There is also a compose action that lets you set the post text and even attach the last photo.</p>

<p>To launch Cross Post, use the URL:</p>

<p><strong>wpscrosspost://</strong></p>

<p>To compose a new post, use:</p>

<p><strong>wpscrosspost://compose?text=[text]&amp;attachment=photo:last</strong></p>

<p>Both parameters are optional. The parameter <em>text</em> can be any text that you want to include in the post. The parameter <em>attachment</em> lets you attach a photo to the post. At the moment <strong>photo:last</strong> is the only supported value for <em>attachment</em> parameter.</p>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[ANN: Cross Post, Sharing Across Social Sites Made Simple]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.whitepeaksoftware.com/2014/11/20/ann-cross-post-sharing-across-social-sites-made-simple/"/>
    <updated>2014-11-20T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.whitepeaksoftware.com/2014/11/20/ann-cross-post-sharing-across-social-sites-made-simple</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="http://257bf79813094f196f16-bc6ead213ec900841fcf0484ae93cd9e.r62.cf2.rackcdn.com/images/cross-post/crosspost-screenshot.png" alt="image" height="200px" style="float: left; margin: 0 1em 1em 0;" /> I am thrilled to announce the release of <a href="http://www.whitepeaksoftware.com/cross-post">Cross Post</a>, a new app for iPhone and iPad that makes it simple to share your post, photos, and links to Facebook, Twitter, and App.net. I talk in detail <a href="http://www.thecave.com/2014/09/14/cross-posting-to-app.net-facebook-and-twitter/">why I decided to write Cross Post</a> over on my personal blog site, but long story short, I wanted a better way to share my thoughts and photos across different social media sites. And <a href="http://www.whitepeaksoftware.com/cross-post">Cross Post</a> is that better way.</p>

<p>Cross Post is free to download and use, but it has limits. You can post to only one social media site at a time using the free version. This gives you a chance to try out Cross Post without spending a cent. If you decide Cross Post is right for you and you want to post to multiple social media sites at the same time, then unlock everything the app has to offer for just $2.99.</p>

<p>What are you waiting for? <a href="https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/cross-post/id872543786?mt=8&amp;uo=4&amp;at=11lcj9&amp;ct=blog">Download Cross Post</a> from the App Store now.</p>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
