<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: announcements | White Peak Software Blog]]></title>
  <link href="http://blog.whitepeaksoftware.com/category/announcements/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://blog.whitepeaksoftware.com/"/>
  <updated>2013-11-18T11:53:25-05:00</updated>
  <id>http://blog.whitepeaksoftware.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Kirby Turner]]></name>
    
  </author>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[ANN: Big Screen Out in the Wild Early]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.whitepeaksoftware.com/2013/11/17/big-screen-out-in-the-wild-early/"/>
    <updated>2013-11-17T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.whitepeaksoftware.com/2013/11/17/big-screen-out-in-the-wild-early</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Last night I made a <a href='https://twitter.com/kirbyt/status/401882700048781312'>teaser tweet</a> about <a href='http://www.whitepeaksoftware.com/big-screen'>Big Screen</a> being approved by Apple. The idea was to pique interest in the app I plan to release in a few weeks. But silly me, I forgot to set the available date to a date in the future, and soon after my tweet people were downloading Big Screen. As my friend <a href='http://www.goldenhillsoftware.com'>John Brayton</a> said, I need to “think of it as extending a beta to anyone on the app store.” So with that, I’m happy to announce Big Screen is now available to everyone.</p>

<p>Big Screen is a new app for iOS that displays the camera’s video stream to any AirPlay receiver (i.e., AppleTV). What makes Big Screen different from using, say the built-in Camera app, is that Big Screen does not display any application chrome on the AirPlay receiver. This makes Big Screen ideal for presentations, conferences, and other types of gatherings where large TV monitors are used to show what’s happening on stage to the folks sitting in the back of the room.</p>

<p>There are other uses for Big Screen as well. My son, and other kids, have been using it to play a version of hide and seek. And kids in general seem to enjoy seeing themselves on TV and are finding ways to have fun with Big Screen that I never thought of. I should also mention that while Big Screen is free, I do have plans to hopefully make a few bucks off the app. The next update will include ads (that are displays on the device, not on the AirPlay receiver) and an In-App Purchase option to remove the ads from the app.</p>

<p>So go grab a copy of <a href='http://www.whitepeaksoftware.com/main/store/buy/big-screen'>Big Screen</a>, and let me know what you think.</p>]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[ANN: Learning iPad Programming, 2nd Edition, is on Sale Now]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.whitepeaksoftware.com/2013/05/28/learning-ipad-programming-on-sale-now/"/>
    <updated>2013-05-28T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.whitepeaksoftware.com/2013/05/28/learning-ipad-programming-on-sale-now</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I&#8217;m happy to announce the second edition of <a href='http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/0321885716/ref=as_li_ss_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;camp=1789&amp;creative=390957&amp;creativeASIN=0321885716&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;tag=whitepeaksoft-20'>Learning iPad Programming</a> is now available at your favorite book store.</p>]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[ANN: Product Retirements]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.whitepeaksoftware.com/2013/01/02/ann-product-retirement/"/>
    <updated>2013-01-02T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.whitepeaksoftware.com/2013/01/02/ann-product-retirement</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>It&#8217;s a brand new year, and as the saying goes, out with the old and in with the new.</p>

<p>I mentioned in my <a href='/2012/12/29/year-in-review/'>2012 Year in Review</a> post that I&#8217;m re-focusing my intention on White Peak Software this year. In some was this re-focus is like a re-boot for WPS. This means exciting new things for the company going forward, but it also means it&#8217;s time to good bye a couple of products.</p>

<p>The first product retiring is SMTP Diagnostics. SMTP Diagnostics was White Peak Software&#8217;s very first product. I honestly did not know if the app would sell or not, nor did I care. I released it because, at the time, it was an app I needed and used regularly. The release of SMTP Diagnostics also gave me the opportunity to learn how to sell software online. Without SMTP Diagnostics, I would not have been as prepared for the other White Peak Software apps.</p>

<p>The second product retiring today is Hey Peanut. Hey Peanut was written for my son Rowan, who was only one and a half at the time. I had high hopes for Hey Peanut. My son loved the app, and I thought other kids would enjoy it as well. I invested time and money into the app, but unfortunately I missed the mark with it. All is not lost though. I learned a lot from the mistakes I made with Hey Peanut that will help me going forward.</p>

<p>It saddens me to see these two apps removed from the White Peak Software home page. Both are very special to me in their own ways. But it is a new year, so out with the old and in with the new.</p>]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[ANN: Office is Open]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.whitepeaksoftware.com/2012/09/10/office-is-open/"/>
    <updated>2012-09-10T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.whitepeaksoftware.com/2012/09/10/office-is-open</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The White Peak Software office is once again open. It&#8217;s back to business as usual.</p>]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[ANN: Office Closed August 22 Through End of September]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.whitepeaksoftware.com/2012/08/20/office-closed/"/>
    <updated>2012-08-20T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.whitepeaksoftware.com/2012/08/20/office-closed</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The White Peak Software office will be closed from Wednesday, August 22, through the end of September.</p>

<p>I am leaving for a month long backpacking trip starting on August 22, and I plan to return by the end of September. Unfortunately I will not have Internet access during this trip, which is why the office will be closed. I apologize in advance for any inconvenience this might cause.</p>

<p>All support emails will be answered in the order they are received once I return.</p>

<p>If you have lost your license information and need it re-sent, click <a href='http://www.whitepeaksoftware.com/support/licenselookup'>here</a> and provide the email address used when the order was placed. Your license information will be retrieved and sent to you via email.</p>

<p>An update to this blog will be posted as soon as the White Peak Software office returned to normal operations.</p>]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>